music
音楽
applause
拍手
come friends
友達来てね
Then I'm here on behalf of Academia Sinica
それでは私は中央研究院を代表してここに来ました
Welcome to our feast of knowledge today
今日は知識の饗宴へようこそ
Our keynote speaker today is
今日の基調講演者は
Chen Yihao, a research fellow of the Institute of Statistical Science of our school
本校統計科学研究所研究員 陳一豪
What about Dr. Chen?
チェン博士はどうですか？
is a research fellow at our Institute of Statistics
私たちの統計研究所の研究員です
National Yang Ming University Institute of Public Health
国立陽明大学公衆衛生研究所
and the Peace of the Department of Mathematics, National Taiwan Normal University
国立台湾師範大学数学科の平和と
and adjunct professor
そして非常勤教授
Dr. Chen graduated from the Electrical Engineering Department of National Taiwan University with a bachelor's degree
チェン博士は国立台湾大学の電気工学科を卒業し、学士号を取得しました。
Then his experience is a bit special
それから彼の経験は少し特別です
He later went to the statistics office of the town university
その後、彼はタウン大学の統計局に行きました。
got a master's degree
修士号を取得しました
Later, I went to National Taiwan University Institute of Public Health
その後、国立台湾大学公衆衛生研究所へ行きました。
Ph.D.
博士号
We can see this development of it
この発展を見ることができます
How to go from motor to statistics
モーターから統計への移行方法
Then I went to the guard's side
それから私は警備員の側に行きました
with this
これとともに
What did you tell us today?
今日は私たちに何を言いましたか？
Earthquake risk again
再び地震の危険性
so this
したがって、この
We can see that this statistic
この統計を見ると、
can contain many, many
たくさんのものが含まれる可能性があります
different facets of science
科学のさまざまな側面
then he is
それなら彼は
in the past served
過去に
Assistant Professor of Mathematics Department of Normal University
師範大学数学科助教授
When he was in 2000
彼が2000年の頃
Entered the Institute of Statistical Science, Academia Sinica
中央研究院統計科学研究所入所
It's been 18 years now
もう18年も経ったんですね
that he was
彼がそうだったということ
what is his research interest
彼の研究興味は何ですか
in statistical methodology
統計的方法論において
Biostatistics etc.
生物統計学など
the nearest research center
最寄りの研究センター
is in survival data analysis
生存データ分析中です
we can all listen
みんなで聞くことができます
Analysis of long-term follow-up data
長期追跡データの分析
Big Data Database Diagnosis
ビッグデータデータベース診断
and analyze incomplete data analysis
不完全なデータ分析を分析する
It sounds like it's all data analysis
すべてはデータ分析のようですね
But it is divided into many aspects
しかし、それは多くの側面に分かれています
Well, he's done an excellent job of research.
そうですね、彼は素晴らしい研究をしました。
He has won the National Science Council
彼は全米科学会議で優勝した
Mr. Wu Dayu Memorial Award of the current Ministry of Education and Technology
現教育技術省呉大夫氏記念賞受賞
This is for young researchers
こちらは若手研究者向けです
The teacher spoke very smoothly
先生はとてもスムーズに話してくれました
And then when you're a bit more senior
そしてもう少し先輩になったら
There's another one called the Distinguished Research Award
もう一つ「優秀研究賞」というものがあります。
Then Mr. Chen also won this research award.
そして、陳氏もこの研究賞を受賞しました。
Then also won the Research Assistant Award for Young Scholars from the China Security Research Institute
その後、中国安全保障研究所から若手研究者研究助手賞も受賞
He also recently supported a deep root project in the courtyard
彼は最近、中庭での根深いプロジェクトも支援しました。
So his researcher is in our younger generation
つまり、彼の研究者は私たちの若い世代にあたります
Or when it comes to the tenured generation, it is a very outstanding one
あるいは、終身在職世代に関して言えば、それは非常に優れた世代です
So today his topic we see here is
さて、今日ここで見る彼のトピックは次のとおりです
Integrative analysis of seismic risk assessment and different databases
地震リスク評価と各種データベースの統合分析
Analysis as an example to tell everyone
皆様にお伝えするための事例としての分析
what statistics do
統計が何をするのか
The first will talk about two practical examples
最初は 2 つの実践的な例について説明します
The first example is statistical methods and techniques
最初の例は統計的手法と技術です。
These introduce some
これらはいくつかの紹介です
some in statistics
統計上の一部
those technologies here
それらのテクノロジーはここにあります
then will
そうすれば
Use this more than 7,000 pens for Taiwan earthquake
7,000本以上のペンを台湾地震に活用
Surface Acceleration Data
表面加速度データ
Established a model for earthquake risk assessment
地震リスク評価モデルを確立
Very useful for earthquake engineers
地震技術者にとって非常に役立ちます
So we can see that the statistical
したがって、統計的に次のことがわかります。
tools in discipline
規律の道具
how do we use it
どのように使用しますか
Then according to the content and characteristics of the seismic survey data
地震探査データの内容や特徴に応じて
How to find these commonalities
これらの共通点を見つける方法
Error and Uncertainty of Velocity Data
速度データの誤差と不確実性
Of course, what we want most is to be able to accurately predict
もちろん、私たちが最も望んでいるのは、正確に予測できることです。
These
これらは
These surface accelerations and the risk of earthquakes
これらの表面加速度と地震の危険性
can make a good assessment
良い評価ができる
so where should i live
それでどこに住めばいいですか
Or maybe we can listen to it today
それとも今日聴けるかも
Can you tell which places in Taiwan are safer?
台湾のどこが安全か分かりますか?
Then the second example is to use introductory statistics
2 番目の例は、入門統計を使用することです。
How can we, in our current era of so-called big data
いわゆるビッグデータの時代に、私たちはどうすればよいでしょうか。
Can be combined with many of the increasingly popular
ますます人気が高まっている多くの製品と組み合わせることができます
There are also a large number of electronic databases
電子データベースも多数あります
So from these databases you can
したがって、これらのデータベースから次のことができます
Long and short
長くて短い
Then we need to sort out accurate and useful information
次に、正確で有益な情報を整理する必要があります
So this is the second question
それでは2番目の質問です
Integrated analysis of different databases
異なるデータベースの統合分析
So now we have a lot of databases in Taiwan
現在、台湾には多くのデータベースがあります
We have a database of health insurance
健康保険のデータベースがあります
and the National Health Interview Survey database
国民健康面接調査のデータベースもあります
Just use this as an example
これを例として使用してください
Then use the large amount of statistical probability above
次に、上記の大量の統計的確率を使用します。
So to explore the relationship between some diseases
したがって、いくつかの病気の間の関係を調査するには
For example, in medicine, there is a difference between a banded foam pillow and chronic obstructive pulmonary disease.
たとえば、医学では、バンド付きフォーム枕と慢性閉塞性肺疾患の間には違いがあります。
There is still some connection
まだつながりはある
So this is why I said that even if it is not a scientist in medicine
だから私は、医学者でなくても、と言いました。
Then we start from this seemingly abstract and somewhat cold statistics
次に、この一見抽象的でやや冷たい統計から始めます。
But we thought we could make some connections
しかし、私たちは何らかのつながりを築くことができると考えました
So today we are very happy to have our speaker Chen Yihao
今日は、陳一豪氏をスピーカーにお迎えできることをとてもうれしく思います
Researchers come to tell us what statistics are doing
研究者がやって来て、統計が何をしているのかを教えてくれる
Now please welcome our keynote speaker today with warm applause
それでは、本日の基調講演者を温かい拍手でお迎えください。
Well, thank you very much for the invitation and introduction from the head of the seat
それでは、議席長からのお誘いとご紹介、誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for participating in our variety show
バラエティ番組にご出演いただき誠にありがとうございました
This is the experience activity of each college
各大学の体験活動はこちら
Everyone has a day's work
誰もが一日の仕事を持っています
or a day of class
または授業の日
And then stay here at night
そして夜はここに泊まってください
Thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
That
それか
Vice President Zhou just introduced
周副主席が先ほど紹介した
Let me introduce to you very clearly what I want to talk about today.
今日話したいことをわかりやすく紹介しましょう。
That
それか
That's because I, as a
それは、私としては、
statistics this
統計はこれ
In this study of statistics
この統計の研究では
I also
私も
Experienced
経験豊富な
If you start counting from the doctoral dissertation
博士論文から数えると
It's been more than 20 years
20年以上経ちますね
so i think
だから私は思う
if i want to be here today
今日ここにいたいなら
Just enjoy what to say
ただ何を言うかを楽しんでください
I can probably only say
たぶんこれしか言えない
topic like this
このような話題
just to let everyone know
みんなに知らせるためだけに
In the end statistics
最終的には統計
These read statistics
これらの読み取り統計
what the hell are they doing
彼らは一体何をしているのですか
because doing may have
なぜなら、そうすることで
many must
多くの人がそうしなければなりません
It is not common for people who have the opportunity to come into contact with statistics
統計に触れる機会がある人はなかなかいないでしょう。
The background of this picture is the Statistics Institute of Academia Sinica
この写真の背景は中央研究院統計研究所です。
is where I work
私が働いている場所です
In fact, it is directly opposite the Academic Activity Center
実は学術活動センターの真向かいにあります
past this lawn
この芝生を越えて
So if you are free, you are welcome to do it.
ですので、お暇な方はぜひやってみてください。
good
良い
That
それか
So at the beginning, I will briefly introduce some background of statistics.
そこで最初に、統計の背景を簡単に紹介します。
The English of statistics is this statistics
統計の英語はこのstatisticsです
That word actually evolved from the word state.
この言葉は実際には状態という言葉から発展しました。
that state we know its
私たちが知っているその状態
it means country
それは国を意味します
so
それで
Indeed, statistics
まさに、統計
Its main job is to
その主な仕事は、
the government or ruler of a country
国の政府または統治者
In order to understand some of the current situation in his country
彼の国の現状を理解するために
For example, the population
たとえば、人口
then this
それからこれ
How much is this income?
この収入はいくらですか？
How many agricultural products are there?
農産物はどれくらいありますか？
How many cows and how many sheep?
牛は何頭、羊は何頭ですか？
hope to have these numbers
これらの数字が得られることを願っています
what about the government
政府はどうですか
So what about statistics at that time?
では、当時の統計はどうだったのでしょうか？
is doing something like this
このようなことをしています
So it’s actually equivalent to what we’re talking about today.
したがって、これは実際に私たちが今日話していることと同じです。
government statistics
政府統計
just like us today
今日の私たちと同じように
like us in taiwan
台湾の私たちのように
Government agency host office
政府機関のホストオフィス
The Statistics Office of the Ministry of Economic Affairs and the Ministry of Health and Welfare
経済部統計局、保健福祉部統計局
what they are doing
彼らは何をやってるの
is very similar to
に非常に似ています
What about the statistics at that time?
当時の統計はどうなっているのでしょうか？
Because the data at that time
当時のデータなので
Mainly probably because at the time
主におそらく当時のせいで
The amount of data at that time was not as large and complex as it is today
当時のデータ量は今日ほど大きくも複雑でもありませんでした
So in fact, the data at that time were mainly obtained through censuses.
ですから、実際のところ、当時のデータは主に国勢調査によって得られたものでした。
That is, the entire country has been investigated
つまり国全体が調査されている
So the main work of statistics at this time
したがって、現時点での統計の主な仕事は
In fact, it is to do the so-called data summary
実際には、いわゆるデータの要約を行うことです。
It is the work of summarizing the data
データをまとめる作業です
It's like when we were young, we were in elementary or middle school
僕らが幼い頃、小学生か中学生だったような気がする
A little basic statistics we learned
私たちが学んだちょっとした基本的な統計
We are doing this so-called data summary, right?
いわゆるデータ集計というのをやっているわけですよね。
For example, we might count
たとえば、次のように数えます。
Let's be honest and ask us to calculate an average of some data
正直に言って、いくつかのデータの平均を計算してもらいましょう
Calculate the median of some data
いくつかのデータの中央値を計算する
the standard deviation of the data
データの標準偏差
then this is
それならこれは
The so-called Data Summary
いわゆるデータサマリー
Summary's Testase
サマリーのテスターゼ
is to put the original many numbers
元の多くの数字を入れることです
many numbers
たくさんの数字
we may not have time to see it
私たちにはそれを見る時間がないかもしれない
Or don't want to see it at all
もしくは全く見たくない
but we put it
しかし、私たちはそれを置きました
only minus
マイナスだけ
Digest it into a few important numbers
それをいくつかの重要な数字に分解します
Through these simple numbers
これらの単純な数字を通して
we can understand this
私たちはこれを理解できます
thousands of data
何千ものデータ
general picture
全体像
we can understand it inside
私たちはそれを内側で理解することができます
contains the message
メッセージが含まれています
good
良い
So actually
それで実際には
what about this thing
これはどうですか
maybe look say
たぶん見て言ってください
This is before the 19th century
これは19世紀以前のものです
maybe
多分
Um
えーっと
very traditional
非常に伝統的な
or very
または非常に
maybe very boring
たぶんとても退屈
like when we were kids
私たちが子供の頃のように
Although the average
平均的ですが、
it's just a process
それは単なるプロセスです
but behind it
しかしその背後にある
actually
実際
There is also a very important statistical theory
非常に重要な統計理論もあります
that is
あれは
it rises
それは上がる
Adequacy of our statistical theory
統計理論の妥当性
That is to say, how do you use a few simple
つまり、いくつかの簡単な機能をどのように使用しますか?
very few numbers
非常に少ない数
will be able to grasp thousands of
何千もの情報を把握できるだろう
Especially when it comes to big data
特にビッグデータに関しては
so much data
とても多くのデータ
when you have no way to see it
見る方法がないとき
Through a few data
いくつかのデータを通じて
to be able to summarize the key points
要点を要約できるようになる
information in it
その中の情報
That thing is actually
あれは実は
In our statistical theory
私たちの統計理論では
very important so-called sufficiency
非常に重要ないわゆる十分性
sufficient statistics
充分統計量
sufficient statistic
十分な統計
such a concept
そのような概念
then next
それから次へ
after the 19th century
19世紀以降
Statistics began to develop differently
統計は異なる発展を始めた
We call it modern statistic
私たちはそれを現代統計と呼んでいます
at this time
現時点では
mainly depends on
主に～に依存します
At this time, the incentives developed by Bloomberg
現時点では、ブルームバーグが開発したインセンティブ
Probability. We learned a little about probability when we were kids, right?
確率: 私たちは子供の頃に確率について少し学びましたよね?
There is a little chance of losing Size
サイズが失われる可能性がわずかにあります
One in six is ​​a probability, right?
6分の1って確率ですよね？
That
それか
Because of the tools of probability
確率というツールがあるから
Then our Institute of Statistics and Probability
それから私たちの統計と確率研究所
What about some tools developed?
開発されたツールについてはどうですか?
At this time, the focus of statistics
今回の統計の焦点は、
The point is never just what I just said
重要なのは、私が今言ったことだけではありません
census data
国勢調査データ
What about the data we care about now?
私たちが今関心を持っているデータはどうなるのでしょうか?
also includes the so-called
いわゆるものも含まれます
Sampling
サンプリング
right
右
The data obtained by sampling
サンプリングによって得られたデータ
Then use probability
次に、確率を使用します
What about some tools developed in probability theory?
確率論で開発されたツールについてはどうでしょうか?
What about statistics?
統計についてはどうですか？
Can these tools be used to deal with it?
これらのツールを使用して対処できますか?
Because of the randomness in the sampled data
サンプリングされたデータにはランダム性があるため、
randomness
ランダム性
I think you can imagine that
それは想像できると思います
today if we were to
今日もしそうするとしたら
For example, this one at our site
たとえば、これは私たちのサイトにあります
Among the audience friends
観客の友人の中には
Draw these 10 people out
この10人を引き出します
Of course, there is a lot of randomness in this
もちろん、これにはランダム性がかなりあります
great uncertainty
大きな不確実性
maybe these people
たぶんこの人たち
maybe those people will be selected
もしかしたらそういう人たちが選ばれるかもしれない
so
それで
This is what is meant by randomness
これがランダム性の意味です
how to deal with this
これにどう対処するか
randomness
ランダム性
How to deal with this kind of randomness and uncertainty
この種のランダム性と不確実性にどう対処するか
find a pattern
パターンを見つける
then this is the time
それなら今がその時だ
A focus of statistics
統計の焦点
The tools used are mainly
使用する道具は主に、
tools of probability
確率の道具
So this time statistics
そこで今回は統計
its main job
その主な仕事
Besides what I just said
今言ったこと以外に
What about data summary
データの概要についてはどうですか
What about finding the so-called sufficient statistics?
いわゆる十分な統計を見つけることについてはどうですか?
In addition
加えて
There is still one
まだ1つあります
The point is what we call statistical inference
重要なのは統計的推論と呼ばれるものです
statistical inference
統計的推論
Okay, statistical inference, what does statistical inference mean?
さて、統計的推論、統計的推論とはどういう意味ですか?
That is, because our current data
つまり、現在のデータでは
Probably only a small part of the whole group
おそらくグループ全体のほんの一部にすぎません
Like we poll, right? We sample
世論調査と同じですよね? 私たちはサンプリングをします
Objects of these visits sampled by this call
この呼び出しによってサンプリングされたこれらの訪問のオブジェクト
Just a small part of the whole group
グループ全体のほんの一部
But we want to take advantage of this sampled fraction
しかし、このサンプリングされた部分を活用したいと考えています。
you can speculate, deduce the whole group's
グループ全体の状況を推測したり推測したりすることができます
a phenomenon a result
一個現象 一個結果
so this is
それでこれは
This so-called modern statistics
このいわゆる現代統計は、
an important thing to do
やるべき重要なこと
The work of so-called statistical inference
いわゆる統計的推論の仕事
So the purpose is to get out of the sampled samples
つまり、目的はサンプリングされたサンプルから抜け出すことです
guess the larger group behind us
おそらくこの大きなグループが私たちの後ろにいます
The situation of classification or the real situation behind it
トリアージの状況またはその背後にある本当の状況
So here are two simple examples
ここで 2 つの簡単な例を示します
That's what I think, everyone may be better than everyone
そう思うよ、みんながみんなより上手いかもしれない
Expose to examples of statistics that are commonly heard
よく聞かれる統計の例を理解する
Well, this is actually what we call Modern statistics
まあ、これは実際には現代統計と呼ばれるものです
Now very widely used
現在では非常に広く使用されています
One example of this is this poll
その一例がこの世論調査です
Or an example of what we call statistically confidence intervals
または統計的に信頼区間と呼ばれるものの例
That passage is actually from this
その一節は実際にはここからのものです
directly on a medium
媒体上に直接
Just copied it down, directly copied it up
それをコピーしただけ、直接コピーした
Then this survey is commissioned by a certain organization to a certain polling company
そして、この調査はある団体からある世論調査会社に委託されています。
From March 12th to 15th, 2018
2018年3月12日から15日まで
For the north and the north and the region
北と北と地域のために
Adults over the age of 64 who fly business jets
ビジネスジェットを利用する64歳以上の成人
A survey of coal-fired power plants was successfully visited
石炭火力発電所の視察に成功
1079 people are below 95% confidence level
1,079 人が信頼水準 95% を下回っています
The sampling error is 2.98 percentage points for the government
政府のサンプリング誤差は 2.98 パーセント ポイントです
I think everyone sees this
これはみんな見てると思うよ
When seeing such a text
このような文章を見ると、
or when you hear something like this
またはこのようなことを聞​​いたとき
should feel familiar
親しみを感じるはずです
right
右
Because it seems that we can often hear
ってよく聞かれるようなので
The results of such polls
そうした世論調査の結果は
that is to say
つまり
Why is there this sampling error
なぜこのようなサンプリングエラーが発生するのでしょうか
This government 2.98 percent
この政府は2​​.98パーセント
This number comes out like this
この数字はこんな感じで出てきます
Why is there a 95% confidence level?
なぜ 95% の信頼水準があるのでしょうか?
Such numbers come out
こういう数字が出てくるんですね
In fact, this reflects
実際、これは反映されています
Our current statistics
現在の統計
Not just to understand this 1079-bit sampling sample
この 1079 ビットのサンプリング サンプルを理解するだけではありません
It's just the result
それはただ結果です
In fact, we are more important from these 1079 bits
実際、これらの 1079 ビットの方が重要です
In this sampled sample
このサンプリングされたサンプルでは
To estimate in the end Jeonbuk
最終的に全北を推定するには
adults in their area
自分たちの地域の大人たち
Their opinions on this public housing and coal-fired power plant
この公営住宅と石炭火力発電所についての意見
how is it
どうですか
Because you have to infer a
推測する必要があるため、
a large group
大きなグループ
It's like you're trying to understand the whole iceberg from the tip
まるで氷山の先端から全体を理解しようとしているようです
So there will be a little error in this
したがって、これには多少の誤差が生じるでしょう
We have to allow a little error
多少の誤差は許容しなければなりません
So there will be this sampling error
したがって、このサンプリングエラーが発生します
2.98 percentage points
2.98パーセントポイント
Such numbers run out
そんな数は足りなくなる
that is to say
つまり
I would like to ask those present
出席者にお聞きしたいのですが
Dear friends here
親愛なる友人の皆様
That is, have you noticed this?
つまり、これに気づきましたか？
The number 1079 and the two numbers 2.98%
1079 という数字と 2 つの数字 2.98%
Have you found any connection between them?
それらの間に何かつながりは見つかりましたか?
can we be this
これでいいですか
I don't know if there are comments
コメントがあるかどうかはわかりませんが、
That is to say, can this
つまり、これはできるでしょうか
Give it a shot, but there are statisticians here.
試してみてください。ただし、ここには統計学者がいます。
here are
ここにあります
A better statistician than me is sitting here
私より優れた統計学者がここに座っています
so you can't fight
だから戦えないんだよ
Have you found out whether this 1079 has anything to do with this 2.98%
この 1079 がこの 2.98% と関係があるかどうかわかりましたか?
sorry
ごめん
3% error
3%的誤差
But this 3% or 2.98% is different from 10
しかし、この 3% または 2.98% は 10 とは異なります。
79 What's the matter?
79 どうしたの？
There is still a mathematical relationship
まだ数学的な関係が残っています
right
右
yes it's his
はい、それは彼のです
It's him
彼だよ
But he has a definite mathematical formula
しかし彼には明確な数式がある
right
右
1079 how to get 2.98%
1079 2.98%を取得する方法
Do you have a quicker mental calculation?
もっと早い暗算ができますか？
that is
あれは
Find out how this 2.98 came from
この 2.98 がどのようにして生まれたのかを調べてください
Where did this error come from?
このエラーはどこから来たのでしょうか?
Even better, this Vice President Zhou is too smart
さらに言えば、この周副主席は賢すぎる。
It is indeed better
確かにその方が良いです
It's better to drive and then count down
運転してからカウントダウンしたほうがいいよ
that is
あれは
3.4 Yes because there is another 20% off
3.4 さらに 20% オフがあるのではい
We have to multiply by 0.98 but usually that 0.98 we just
0.98 を掛ける必要がありますが、通常は 0.98 を掛けるだけです。
don't care
気にしないでください
So it's almost
それで、ほぼ
root sign open root sign
ルートサイン オープンルートサイン
that's what we call statistics
それが私たちが統計と呼ぶものです
A word we statisticians say most often
私たち統計学者が最もよく言う言葉
is the square root n
平方根nです
The root sign n is the number of samples
ルート記号 n はサンプル数です
So the square root n is in our statistics
したがって、平方根 n が統計に含まれます。
is a magic number
は魔法の数字です
root sign n so everyone today
ルートサインnなので皆さん今日は
you will know
あなたは知るだろう
what statisticians do
統計学者は何をするのか
In fact, it is very simple, it is the root number n
実際、それは非常に単純で、根数 n です。
so later you see this
それで後でこれを見ます
When the news is broadcasting the results of this poll again
ニュースでこの世論調査の結果が再び放送されるとき
When this reporter is still talking
この記者がまだ話しているとき
When successfully interviewing 1079 people
1079人へのインタビューに成功した場合
you can figure it out right away
あなたはすぐにそれを理解することができます
Incorrect sampling is a percentage point sent by the government
不正確なサンプリングは政府から通知されるパーセントポイントです
then your child your friend
それからあなたの子供はあなたの友達です
must adore you
あなたを崇拝する必要があります
Then the second example is
次に、2番目の例は次のとおりです
p-value I want to do it again
p値もう一度やりたい
If there is this to engage in scientific research
これがあれば科学研究に従事できます
especially this biomedical
特にこの生物医学
or social science
または社会科学
of this research
この研究の
Probably very familiar with P-value
おそらく P 値についてはよく知っているでしょう
Because I have to follow this P-value all day long
一日中このP値に従わなければならないからです
deal, right?
取引ですよね？
because we basically
なぜなら私たちは基本的に
we do an experiment
私たちは実験をします
we want to see this experiment
私たちはこの実験を見たいです
Is it the result of the experiment
実験の結果ですか
Is it enough to support
サポートするだけで十分ですか
Results of our experiments
実験結果
it is indeed a
それは確かに
a significant result
重要な結果
when shrinking
縮むとき
Then P-value
次に P 値
Its size basically reflects the
そのサイズは基本的に
Such experimental data
このような実験データ
it supports
それはサポートします
Experimental results
実験結果
did not have this
これは持っていませんでした
full of this salience
この顕著性に満ちています
such a contraction
そのような収縮
so
それで
If the number of this P-value is larger
このP値の数値が大きい場合
If the number of p value is larger
p値の数が大きい場合
For example like this 0.452
たとえばこのように 0.452
p value must be connected between 0 and 1
p 値は 0 と 1 の間で接続する必要があります
So if the number of p value is larger
したがって、p 値の数が大きい場合は、
It means that the degree of your support is not significant is higher
あなたのサポートの程度が大きくないことを意味します
So your result is not significant
したがって、あなたの結果は重要ではありません
your result is not significant
あなたの結果は重要ではありません
Conversely, if this value is smaller
逆に値が小さければ
means you support your data
データをサポートしていることを意味します
The results of your experiment support this conclusion significantly
あなたの実験結果はこの結論を大きく裏付けています
is insignificant the less the extent to which such hypotheses
そのような仮説の程度が低いほど重要ではない
The smaller the degree of insignificance
無意味度が小さいほど
that represents your result
それはあなたの結果を表します
The degree of significance is higher
重要度が高くなります
So we generally do scientific research
したがって、私たちは通常、科学的研究を行います
is to hope that our p value
私たちの p 値が期待されることです
is the smaller the better
小さいほど良いですか
Because this means that our experimental results are more significant
これは実験結果がより重要であることを意味するためです
So this is also an example
ということで、これも一例です
That is to say, this modern statistical
つまり、この現代の統計学は、
is what we call an inferential statistic
これは私たちが推論統計と呼ぶものです
is a statistical inference
統計的推論です
Because like P-Failure
なぜならP-Failのように
He just wants to learn from the samples you experimented with
彼はあなたが実験したサンプルから学びたいだけなのです
to infer the results of real science
現実の科学の結果を推測する
Is it of sufficient significance
十分な意味があるのか
good
良い
So basically we can say
基本的に言えることは
this statistic
この統計
statistics is special
統計は特別です
Although it is a
ですが、
so to speak from mathematics
いわば数学から
A discipline developed from applied mathematics
応用数学から発展した学問
But it is different from traditional mathematics
しかし、それは伝統的な数学とは異なります
Traditional Applied Mathematics
伝統的な応用数学
there is a very different place
とても違う場所があります
just to say
ただ言うために
traditional mathematics
伝統的な数学
more focus on the natural world
自然界にもっと焦点を当てましょう
a very definite rule
非常に明確なルール
good
良い
That
それか
it's theirs
これは彼らのものです
research object, such as Einstein's
アインシュタインなどの研究対象
1st class Mc squared or Newton's
1級Mc二乗またはニュートンの
The constant rate of Newton's motion F and other MA these things
ニュートン運動の一定速度 F およびその他の MA これらのこと
These are a very definite, very definite
これらは非常に明確で、非常に明確です
a law of nature
自然の法則
That's what statisticians focus on
統計学者が注目しているのはそこだ
is dealing with
を扱っています
We are everywhere in our daily life
私たちは日常生活のどこにでもいます
This so-called uncertainty
このいわゆる不確実性
One of the founding fathers of this America
このアメリカ建国の父の一人
Franklin once said
フランクリンはかつてこう言った
There are only two things that are certain in life
人生で確かなことは2つだけ
everything else is uncertain
それ以外はすべて不確かです
Do you know what those two things are?
その２つが何なのか知っていますか？
Death and taxes, right?
死と税金ですよね？
It's May 1st and we have to pay taxes again, right?
5月1日なので、また税金を支払わなければなりませんよね？
So only death and paying taxes are two things
つまり、死と税金の支払いだけが二つのことなのです
Everything else is uncertain
それ以外はすべて未定です
Then we statisticians are actually
それでは、私たち統計学者は実際には
with these main
これらのメインで
The problems to be dealt with are these
対処すべき問題は次のとおりです
with uncertainty
不確実性を伴う
related questions
関連する質問
The so-called statistical model
いわゆる統計モデル
Its point is to go
ポイントは行くことです
going to portray
描写するつもり
and to assess the magnitude of this uncertainty
そしてこの不確実性の大きさを評価するために
Then the so-called statistical inference
次に、いわゆる統計的推論
is to exist in uncertainty
不確実性の中に存在するということ
make statistical inferences in the current situation
現在の状況で統計的な推論を行う
go from the tip of the iceberg
氷山の一角から行く
infer the truth
真実を推測する
So in the statistical chart
それで、統計図では
we often see
私たちがよく見るもの
not just one result
一つの結果だけではなく
Instead there will be a
代わりに、
a degree of change up and down
上下の変化の程度
represents the uncertainty
不確実性を表します
this error this possibility
このエラー この可能性
Another number term in our statistics is called
私たちの統計におけるもう 1 つの数値項は、
Mutations
突然変異
variation
変化
variation跟certity
バリエーションと証明書
It is the same as arrow to some extent
矢印とある程度同じです
good
良い
That
それか
Statisticians are mainly
統計学者は主に、
Statistics is mainly to
統計というのは主に、
go
行く
To make statistical inferences amidst these uncertainties
こうした不確実性の中で統計的な推論を行うには
then making statistical inferences
それから統計的な推論を行う
What we pay more attention to is actually not the final result.
私たちがより注意を払うのは、実際には最終結果ではありません。
This result may be anyone can get one
この結果は誰でも手に入れることができるかもしれません
some kind of result, right?
何らかの結果ですよね？
But what?
でも何？
What about statistics?
統計についてはどうですか？
It pays more attention to the process of getting this result
この結果を得るプロセスにさらに注目します
this process
このプロセス
That is, we would like to say that the process is a
つまり、このプロセスは
best way
最良の方法
The best
最高の
A sort of
一種
ar
と
program to get the result of this inference
この推論の結果を取得するプログラム
So the so-called
それで、いわゆる
This is what we call this statistical inference
これを統計的推論と呼びます
This optimality in statistical inference
統計的推論におけるこの最適性
Optimality
最適性
That's a matter of great importance in statistics.
それは統計において非常に重要な問題です。
matter of great importance
非常に重要な問題
So when we use statistics to make inferences,
したがって、統計を使用して推論を行う場合、
There must be a so-called objective function
いわゆる目的関数が存在する必要があります
Our objective function
私たちの目的関数
Usually a so-called likely-who direction
通常、いわゆる「可能性の高い人物」の方向
likely-who is a possibility
可能性が高い - 可能性があるのは誰ですか
likelihood function
尤度関数
This likelihood refers to a statistical model
この可能性は統計モデルを指します
which produces the data we observe
私たちが観察するデータを生成するもの
such a possibility
そんな可能性
such a likely-who
そんな可能性が高い-誰
So this direction we call the likely-who direction
したがって、この方向を私たちは可能性の高い方向と呼んでいます
so a good model
とても良いモデルです
It should make this like-if
これは like-if になるはずです
how about the direction
方向はどうですか
The bigger the better, right?
大きいほど良いですよね？
Because it means that this model
ということはこのモデルは
is more likely to produce
生成する可能性が高くなります
Is the data we see right now?
私たちが今見ているデータは正しいのでしょうか?
So that means
つまり、
This model follows us
このモデルは当社の
The data actually seen is the best fit
実際に見たデータが最適です
right? that's what it means
そうですか、それが意味です
so our
だから私たちの
we will have so-called
いわゆる
maximum likelihood
最大の可能性
method of such inference
そのような推論の方法
In fact, in some cases
実際、場合によってはこの方法
would also be equivalent to
また、次と同等になります
more often heard
より頻繁に聞かれる
The so-called minimum frequency method
いわゆる最小周波数法
minimum frequency method
最小周波数法
well then
じゃあ
In addition, our so-called
さらに、私たちのいわゆる
optimality
最適性
our best
私たちの最高の
also includes the so-called consistency
いわゆる一貫性も含まれます
consistency
一貫性
another way of saying it
別の言い方
law of large numbers
大数の法則
You may hear this name more often.
この名前をよく聞くかもしれません。
Then his statistical comparison
次に、彼の統計的比較
the professional term
専門用語
called consistency
一貫性と呼ばれる
consistency
一貫性
what he meant was basically
彼が言いたかったのは基本的には
We want the outcome of our statistical inference
統計的推論の結果が必要です
With the number of samples
サンプル数に応じて
when getting bigger
大きくなって
He was able to get closer and closer to the real result
彼は実際の結果にどんどん近づくことができました
this is called consistency
これを一貫性と呼びます
consistency
一貫性
on the other hand
一方で
we also hope
私たちも願っています
In addition to this consistency
この一貫性に加えて、
The results of our statistical inferences
統計的推論の結果
effective
効果的
Efficiency
効率
that means
つまり
we hope
望みでは
because of sampling
サンプリングのせいで
different sampling
異なるサンプリング
have caused changes
変化を引き起こした
because just now
ちょうど今だから
These data and data are all sampled.
これらのデータとデータはすべてサンプリングされています。
So different sampling will lead to different results
したがって、サンプリングが異なると結果も異なります
right
右
We expect such different outcome variations
このようなさまざまな結果のバリエーションが予想されます
The smaller the impact on the outcome, the better
結果への影響が小さいほど良い
The smaller the better
小さいほど良い
This variation with sampling
サンプリングによるこの変化
What about the change in the result?
結果の変化はどうでしょうか？
What about the smaller
小さい方はどうですか
We say that its efficiency is higher
効率が高いと言われています
the more efficient it is the better
効率が良ければ良いほど良い
What about statistical theory?
統計理論についてはどうですか？
In fact, it also gives
実際、それはまた、
In fact, we are in the general problem
実際、私たちは一般的な問題に直面しています
If we want to make statistical inferences
統計的な推論を行いたい場合
In fact, we have a best standard
実際、私たちには最高の基準があります
That is the so-called information bound
それがいわゆる情報束縛です
This means our efficiency
これは私たちの効率を意味します
best possible
可能な限り最善の
highest efficiency
最高的efficiency
That is, the minimum degree of change
つまり、最小限の変化
With the change of sampling
サンプリングによるバリエーション
minimum degree of change
最小限の変化
good so
いいですね
Such an Information Bound
このような情報の束縛
just told us one like a
ちょうど私たちに次のようなことを言いました
test tell you
テストして教えてください
What is the full score of this test
このテストの満点は何点ですか
so you have a goal
だからあなたには目標があります
You can move towards that goal
その目標に向かって進むことができる
If you still can't reach that goal
それでもその目標に到達できない場合
You can also know that
つまり、あなたも知ることができます
How much room do you have to work hard
頑張れる余地はどれくらいある？
Then this Efficiency
次に、この効率
This Information Bound
この情報は拘束されています
involved a
関与した
defined by our statistics
私たちの統計によって定義される
Information
情報
Everyone is saying this word every day
誰もが毎日この言葉を言っています
Information Information message, right?
情報 情報メッセージですよね？
Then how do we define statistics
では統計をどう定義するか
How much information is there in the so-called data
いわゆるデータにはどれだけの情報が含まれているのか
Information basically
基本的に情報
we are based on
私たちは基づいています
This Objective Function just mentioned
先ほど述べたこの目的関数
this objective function
この目的関数
its this
それはこれです
degree of bending
曲がりの程度
That is the so-called curvature Curvature
それがいわゆる曲率です
to define
定義します
Then let me ask you again
それでは、もう一度お聞きします
that is
あれは
Suppose our current goal
現在の目標を仮定します
is the maximum required for this objective function
この目的関数に必要な最大値です
This is the goal of our inference
これが私たちの推論の目標です
Then I want to ask everyone
そこで皆さんに聞きたいのですが
that is
あれは
The red curve on the left
左側の赤いカーブ
with this blue curve on the right
この青い曲線が右側にあります
which curve do you think
どの曲線だと思いますか
Will give you more information
さらに詳しい情報をお知らせします
Your goal is to ask for the maximum value
あなたの目標は最大値を求めることです
What do you think is the red curve
赤い曲線は何だと思いますか
still blue curve
まだ青い曲線
Will give you more information
さらに詳しい情報をお知らせします
Why is it red on the left?
なんで左側が赤いの？
the aunt
叔母さん
right
右
can you tell me
教えて頂けますか
perfectly accurate
完全正確
exactly that's it
まさにこのように
Because of its large difference
その差が大きいため、
so you can easily find
簡単に見つけることができます
where is the best place
一番良い場所はどこですか
right
右
that blue curve
あの青い曲線
you will be more difficult
あなたはもっと難しくなるでしょう
because it feels the same
同じように感じるから
you can hardly find the best
最高のものを見つけるのは難しいでしょう
right
右
so what
だから何
The information of our statistics
当社の統計情報
is through the curvature of our target content
ターゲットコンテンツの曲率を介して行われます
Then we start from this elementary
それではこの初歩的なことから始めましょう
we also know
私たちも知っています
In fact, the curvature of a curve
実際、曲線の曲率は
In fact, you can directly use this curve
実際、この曲線を直接使用することもできます。
Secondary differentiation gives
二次微分すると、
right
右
So this is how we
このようにして私たちは
To measure the information in this data
このデータの情報を測定するには
So this information
それでこの情報は
not just talk
ただ話すだけではなく
In fact, our statistics have a clear way
実際、私たちの統計には明確な方法があります
To measure this information
この情報を測定するには
In addition we have the so-called
さらに、いわゆる
near normality
正常に近い
It is also well-known in our statistics
私たちの統計でもよく知られています
central limit theorem
中心極限定理
This is mainly to describe
これは主に説明するためのものです
Sampling
サンプリング
When sampling is changing
サンプリングが変化するとき
How the results of our statistical inferences change
統計的推論の結果はどのように変化するか
we want to say it will change
私たちは変わりますと言いたいのです
But its change must have a law
しかし、その変化には法則がなければなりません
what's the rule
ルールは何ですか
There will be such a law as the normal distribution
正規分布のような法則が成り立つだろう
so that we can have a
できるように
very convenient way to measure
非常に便利な測定方法
to calculate the uncertainty
不確実性を計算するには
Uncertainty due to sampling
サンプリングによる不確実性
So here is an example
ここに例があります
Like this is the law of large numbers
これが大数の法則のようなものです
Everyone may have seen this
これを見たことがあるかもしれません
That is to say, this S8 is the average of our sample
つまり、この S8 はサンプルの平均です。
The one below 41 445
41 445 の下のもの
4,6,7,18 This is its sample number
4,6,7,18 これはサンプル番号です
What about when you increase the number of samples
サンプル数を増やすとどうなるか
You will find that this S8 slowly and slowly
このS8はゆっくりとゆっくりと
close to a number
数値に近い
In fact, it is close to 0.5, which is the one in our picture.
実際には、この写真にある 0.5 に近い値です。
red line
レッドライン
Then this 0.5 is indeed
そうすると、この 0.5 は確かに
average for this group
このグループの平均
So this picture is to tell you
だからこの写真はあなたに伝えたいのです
a thing called the law of large numbers
大数の法則と呼ばれるもの
We just talked about this statistical inference
この統計的推論についてお話しました
What about this statistic?
この統計はどうでしょうか？
will gradually increase with the number of samples
サンプル数に応じて徐々に増加します
close to the mean of our true population
真の人口の平均値に近い
Like that poll, right?
あの世論調査のようなものですよね？
When you poll if you interview more and more people
より多くの人にインタビューすると世論調査が行われるとき
Why
なぜ
The result of this visit is getting closer to
今回の訪問の結果は近づきつつある
The support of the people in this truly all northern and northern accumulation areas
まさにこの北方北方集積地域の皆様のご支援。
how many
幾つか
so
それで
This is called the law of large numbers
これを大数の法則といいます
What about the other thing? This is the central limit theorem just mentioned.
もう一つはどうでしょうか? これは先ほどの中心極限定理です。
normality of eating
食事の正常さ
This is just the average
これはあくまで平均です
it's always changing, right?
それは常に変化していますよね？
But we record all the process of its changes
しかし、私たちはその変化の過程をすべて記録します
and then put all occurrences of
そして、次のすべての出現を入れます
only into one
一つだけに
The so-called fat map, the fat map we learned as children
いわゆるファットマップ、私たちが子供の頃に習ったファットマップ
right
右
Just look at its distribution
その分布を見てみましょう
Distribution from large to small
大規模から小規模までの分布
that's what i just said
それが私が今言ったことです
that is
あれは
Although it will keep moving
動き続けますが
right
右
but you will find
でもあなたは見つけます
this
これ
Well
良い
What is the law of its change?
その変化の法則とは何でしょうか？
actually it
実際それ
Although big and small, right?
大きいのも小さいのもあるけどね？
but you can find
でも見つけることができます
When you fatten all of it from big to small into one
大きいものから小さいものまで全部太らせたら
When the fat map is presented
ファットマップが表示されるとき
It is very close to a normal distribution
正規分布に非常に近いです
What is a normal distribution
正規分布とは何ですか
It's the blue line behind
後ろの青い線です
blue line
青い線
Then the width of this normal distribution
次に、この正規分布の幅は
reflect the extent to which we have changed
私たちがどれだけ変わったかを反映する
right
右
What about the width?
幅についてはどうですか？
Basically what Vice President Zhou just said
基本的には周副主席が今言ったことです
One part of the root of n
n の根の一部
such a width
あんな幅
So the width is just in the process of changing
幅はちょうど変化の途中です
everyone can see
誰もが見ることができます
Because the square root sign is n/1
平方根の符号はn/1なので
So when n gets bigger and bigger
それで、nがどんどん大きくなると
Its width is getting smaller and smaller
その幅はどんどん小さくなっていきます
So the extent of our change is getting smaller and smaller
つまり、私たちの変化の範囲はますます小さくなっています
getting smaller
小さくなる
So we get more and more accurate results
そのため、より正確な結果が得られます
And this level of precision
そしてこのレベルの精度
It is possible to use a very simple normal distribution
非常に単純な正規分布を使用することができます
to characterize it to measure it
特徴づける 測定する
good
良い
Then here I am simple
それではここで私は単純です
When Zhou Fuyuechang was mentioned in the introduction at the beginning, it means
冒頭の紹介で周福月昌について言及したとき、それは次のことを意味します。
In fact, statistics is a
実際、統計というのは、
A knowledge that can be applied in a variety of different fields
さまざまな分野に応用できる知識
In fact, it is also an instrumental science
実はそれは道具的な知識でもある
Just like a computer, like information
コンピューターのように、情報のように
it is used as a tool
それは道具として使われている
can be used for a variety of problems
さまざまな問題に使用できます
good
良い
So actually I thought about it myself and said
それで実際に自分で考えてこう言いました
Statistics for the entire scientific community
科学コミュニティ全体の統計
What major contributions have you made?
あなたはどのような大きな貢献をしましたか?
Then I list these three
それからこの3つを列挙します
But what I want to tell you is to say
でも、私があなたに言いたいのは、
This is only limited to my personal
これはあくまでも私個人に限った話ですが、
because of my own field of study
自分の研究分野のせいで
So I know these three
だから私はこの3つを知っています
Of course other statisticians
もちろん他の統計学者も
may have different answers
異なる答えがあるかもしれません
But I don't think these three are the only three
でもこの3人だけではないと思う
what i just said
私が今言ったこと
But they do, I think, very important contributions
しかし、彼らは非常に重要な貢献をしていると思います
The first is the so-called case control study
1つ目は、いわゆる症例対照研究です。
case control study
症例対照研究
The second is the so-called EM algorithm
2 つ目は、いわゆる EM アルゴリズムです。
The third is the so-called Kephenmeyer curve
3 番目は、いわゆるケフェンマイヤー曲線です。
So let me introduce to you
それではご紹介させていただきます
The first I think is a very big contribution
まず、非常に大きな貢献だと思います
It is a case control study
症例対照研究です
case control study is called case control study in Chinese
症例対照研究は中国語で症例対照研究と呼ばれます
This is now widely used in public health
これは現在公衆衛生で広く使用されています
in medicine in public health
医学、公衆衛生
A research method in the field of epidemiology
疫学分野における研究手法
This method does something like this
このメソッドは次のようなことを行います
That is to say, suppose you want to study Western Tobacco
つまり、西洋タバコを研究したいとします。
Will it be easy to get scrapped
廃車になりやすいのかな
The traditional approach may be that you have to watch a group of
従来のアプローチでは、グループを監視する必要があるかもしれません。
Following a group of CN people
CN の人々のグループをフォローする
Then look at the proportion of them getting lung cancer 5 years later and 10 years later
次に、5年後と10年後に肺がんになる人の割合を見てみましょう。
right
右
Then watch a bunch of this
それからこれをたくさん見てください
People who are not CN, right?
CNじゃない人たちですよね？
Same tracking for 5 years and 10 years
5年後も10年後も同じ追跡
Then look at his rate of getting lung cancer
次に、彼の肺がんの罹患率を調べてください。
Then do a comparison, right?
それから比較してみませんか？
This way you can draw a conclusion saying
このようにして、次のような結論を導き出すことができます
Is there any relationship between CN and lung cancer?
CNと肺がんの間には関係がありますか?
What about proportional control studies?
比例制御の研究についてはどうですか?
he did this
彼はこれをしました
he didn't do that
彼はそんなことしなかった
because doing so
そうするから
you spend a lot of time
あなたは多くの時間を費やします
you're going to track down
あなたは追跡するつもりです
That's what the proportional control study did
それが比例制御の研究で行われたことです
That is to say, he went directly to the hospital
つまり、彼はすぐに病院に行ったということです
Just go to the oncology department, for example, right?
たとえば、腫瘍科に行ってみてください。
He went to find a patient with lung cancer, right?
彼は肺がんの患者を探しに行きましたよね？
Then, for example, he goes to the Chiayi Division again, right?
それで、例えばまた嘉義師団に行くんですよね。
Family medicine, he went to the guy who didn't have lung cancer.
家庭医学、彼は肺がんに罹患していない男のところに行きました。
patients without lung cancer
肺がんのない患者
But he's probably just here to add one for a health check
しかし、彼はおそらく健康診断のために追加するためにここに来ただけでしょう
Or watch a diarrhea or catch a cold
あるいは、下痢や風邪を引いていないか注意してください
so he doesn't have lung cancer
だから彼は肺がんではない
So you go directly to these two groups of people
したがって、これら 2 つのグループの人々に直接アクセスします。
and ask them if they smoke
それから彼らに喫煙するかどうか尋ねます
Then you directly compare
次に、直接比較します
So such a
それで、そのような
The research method is called
研究方法はと呼ばれます
case-control study
症例対照研究
Then this method is from
次に、このメソッドは
Early 20th century around 1910s and 1920s
20世紀初頭、1910年代から1920年代頃
Began to appear in medical professional journals
医療専門誌に掲載され始める
Such studies are beginning to be reported
そういった研究も報告され始めている
The main research object at that time was
当時の主な研究対象は
The relationship between smoking and lung cancer
喫煙と肺がんの関係
And this birth history
そしてこの誕生歴
women's reproductive history
女性の生殖の歴史
has he ever had a child
彼には子供がいたことがありますか
how many children were born
何人の子供が生まれましたか
At what age did he have his first child
彼は何歳で最初の子供を産みましたか
in connection with his subsequent breast cancer
その後の乳がんに関連して
So at the beginning of the 20th century, this kind of
それで、20世紀初頭には、この種の
Case Control study of this kind of research is reported
この種の研究の症例対照研究が報告されています
At that time, at that time, it caused a great deal of
あの時、あの時、大変な事になりました
caused a lot of controversy in the scientific community
科学界で多くの論争を引き起こした
why
なぜ
Because it should be easy for everyone to see
誰にとっても見やすいはずだから
That is to say, traditionally we statistically analyze
つまり、伝統的に統計的に分析します。
so-called representative sample
いわゆる代表サンプル
right? for example
そうですよね？たとえば
We often say that you are clearly inaccurate in the investigation
私たちはよく、あなたの調査は明らかに不正確だと言います。
Because your sample is not representative
サンプルが代表的なものではないため
right
右
So what about our statistical analysis?
では、統計分析についてはどうでしょうか?
What is often required is
よく求められるのは、
Our premise is to have a
私たちの前提は、
representative的sample
代表的なサンプル
The sample obtained from the Case Control study
症例対照研究から得られたサンプル
Obviously not a representative sample
明らかに代表的なサンプルではありません
right
右
For example, if I take 100 today
例えば今日100個取ったら
100 lung cancer patients
肺がん患者100人
With 100 patients without lung cancer
肺がんのない患者が 100 人いる場合
What about this?
これはどうですか？
inside my sample
私のサンプルの中に
The rate of lung cancer is 50%
肺がんの発生率は50％
right
右
But in all Taiwan
でも台湾全体で
of all groups
すべてのグループの
rate of lung cancer
肺がんの発生率
is far less than this 50%
この 50% よりはるかに小さい
right
右
So this sample
それでこのサンプルは
obviously not a
明らかにそうではありません
representative sample
代表的なサンプル
So how can he be used to infer
それで、彼はどうやって推測することができますか
What is the relationship between smoking and lung cancer?
喫煙と肺がんにはどのような関係があるのでしょうか?
or
また
Women's reproductive history with him
彼との女性の生殖歴
What about breast cancer?
乳がんについてはどうですか？
so this time
それで今回は
caused a very, very big debate
非常に大きな議論を引き起こした
So until this about the 1950s
それで1950年代くらいまでは
This is it
これだよ
The statistician Jeromey Kohnfield
統計学者のジェロミー・コーンフィールド
he is this american
彼はこのアメリカ人です
National Cancer Institute
国立がん研究所
a statistician of
の統計学者
He is theoretically
彼は理論的には
from mathematics to statistics
数学から統計まで
In theory to confirm this case control study
この症例対照研究を理論的に裏付けるには
The results of his analysis
彼の分析結果
his effectiveness
彼の有効性
his correctness
彼の正しさ
With you just now you followed the smoker directly
あなたと一緒にあなたは喫煙者を直接追いかけただけです
track non-smokers
非喫煙者を追跡する
Then look at the results of his last illness
それから彼の最後の病気の結果を見てください
This correctness is exactly the same as
この正しさはまったく同じです
He clarified the fact that
彼はその事実を明らかにした
then after him
それから彼の後
There are more and more statisticians
統計学者が増えている
to further develop
さらに発展するために
to refine this sort of case-control study
この種の症例対照研究を改良するため
So some research methods like this
このような調査方法もあります
also facilitated this
これも促進しました
Many studies on this etiology
この病因に関する多くの研究
research on disease prevention
病気の予防に関する研究
in medicine
医学で
so like this guy
この人みたいに
This man is actually an epidemic
この男は実は伝染病だ
Pathologist, he said in his book
病理学者、彼は著書の中でこう述べた。
say it
それを言う
List of sophisticated use and understanding of case control
ケースコントロールの高度な使用法と理解のリスト
studies is the most outstanding
勉強が一番優秀だよ
mestarch development of modern
現代のメスターチの開発
epidemiology
疫学
So he said it himself
だから彼は自分で言ったんだ
modern epidemiology
現代疫学
The word is epidemiology
疫学という言葉は
Epidemiology in modern times
現代の疫学
One of the most outstanding achievements is the
最も優れた成果の 1 つは、
The use and understanding of case-control research methods
症例対照研究手法の使用と理解
behind this
この後ろに
In fact, the biggest contribution is the contribution of statisticians
実際、最大の貢献は統計学者の貢献です
Because it's up to the statisticians to figure it out.
それを解明するのは統計学者次第だからです。
this
これ
case control study his validity his correctness
ケースコントロールの研究 彼の妥当性 彼の正しさ
and further refine his method
そして彼の手法をさらに洗練させます
Okay, the second important contribution I want to make is
さて、私がしたい 2 番目の重要な貢献は、
Statistically important contributions to the scientific community
科学界への統計的に重要な貢献
is the so-called
いわゆる
hospital algorithm
病院のアルゴリズム
So
それで
The hospital algorithm has actually been
病院のアルゴリズムは実際に
used in many, many different fields
非常に多くの異なる分野で使用されています
like
好き
Like this Machine Learning
このように機械学習
very red now
今はとても赤い
active learning
能動的学習
or like medical imaging
または医療画像のようなもの
or something like this
またはこのようなもの
Psychological Dosimetry
心理線量測定
volume psychology
ボリューム心理学
fake finance
偽像財務
Financial Engineering
金融工学
this kind of
このたぐいの
different fields
さまざまな分野
will use this algorithm
このアルゴリズムを使用します
to calculate
計算する
the result they want
彼らが望む結果
What about this method?
この方法はどうでしょうか？
In fact, it was first created by three
実は最初に作ったのは3人
The Harvard Statistics Department
ハーバード大学統計局
proposed by the professor
教授が提案した
about 40 years ago
約40年前
proposed an algorithm
アルゴリズムを提案した
What about this algorithm?
このアルゴリズムはどうでしょうか?
that is
あれは
It basically takes our Model
基本的にモデルを使用します
divided into observed parts
観察された部分に分割される
with the unobserved part
観察されていない部分で
hidden part
隠れた部分
and parameters
およびパラメータ
Then what about the so-called unobserved
では、いわゆる観察されていないものはどうでしょうか
1 here is a 1
1 ここは 1 です
1 what about this thing
1 これはどうですか
means to mean
意味する
You just put the part that you didn't observe
観察していない部分を載せただけです
you take his average
あなたは彼の平均を取る
take one of his expectations
彼の期待の一つを受け入れる
because he can't see
彼は目が見えないから
So you use his expectations to
だからあなたは彼の期待を利用して、
bring it in
それを持ち込んでください
fill it in
記入してください
What about the expected value?
期待値はどうでしょうか？
of course it is
もちろん
conditional expected value
条件付き期待値
It is given in the part we have seen
それは私たちが見た部分に与えられています
and the current parameter value
と現在のパラメータ値
calculated by a
によって計算される
expected expectations
予想される期待
OK, after I bring you in
わかりました、私があなたを連れて行った後
you can like this
これを気に入っていただけますか
You see everything you see, right?
目に見えるものはすべて見えますよね？
So you can directly address the goal just mentioned
したがって、先ほど述べた目標に直接取り組むことができます
Contain numbers to maximize
最大化する数値を含める
Do you want to optimize
最適化しますか?
to get a parameter value
パラメータ値を取得するには
After getting the new parameter value
新しいパラメータ値を取得した後
You go to update the original expectation
元の期待値を更新します
Because this expected value will be related to the parameter value
この期待値はパラメータ値に関係するため、
Go to update and then do the maximum
アップデートに進み、最大限のことを実行します
So this algorithm is an iterative process
したがって、このアルゴリズムは反復プロセスです
it ends up with this
これで終わります
converge to a final result
最終結果に収束する
So one is called E step and the other is called M step
したがって、一方は E ステップと呼ばれ、もう一方は M ステップと呼ばれます
E is to calculate an average, to calculate an expected value
Eは平均を計算する、期待値を計算する
M is to seek the optimization of the target content
Mは対象コンテンツの最適化を図る
So the combination of E and M is the EM algorithm
したがって、E と M の組み合わせが EM アルゴリズムです
So what is the benefit of this algorithm?
では、このアルゴリズムの利点は何でしょうか?
The first one is very general
最初のものは非常に一般的です
It can be used for a variety of different problems
さまざまな問題に使用できます
that is
あれは
You don't need for a different problem
別の問題の場合は必要ありません
to design a different algorithm
別のアルゴリズムを設計する
In fact, later found
実は後から判明したのですが、
Many, many different algorithms that people are already using
人々がすでに使用している非常に多くの異なるアルゴリズム
can be put into the framework of this EM algorithm.
この EM アルゴリズムのフレームワークに組み込むことができます。
So you just need to master this basic principle
したがって、この基本原則をマスターする必要があるだけです
It is the two steps of E and M
EとMの2段です
you will
あなたはするであろう
You can calculate many, many problems
非常に多くの問題を計算できます
So this is a very big contribution
これは非常に大きな貢献です
Another great contribution is that
もう一つの大きな貢献は、
This EM algorithm is a very stable algorithm
このEMアルゴリズムは非常に安定したアルゴリズムです
That is to say, every time it is carried out
つまり、実行されるたびに、
will catch your target
ターゲットを捕まえます
in further optimization
さらなる最適化で
further bigger
さらに大きい
or better
それ以上の
so
それで
It means you're always going in the right direction
つまり、常に正しい方向に進んでいるということです
you won't go wrong
あなたは間違っていないでしょう
you are always going
あなたはいつも行っています
one of the best places to go
行くのに最高の場所の 1 つ
So this is the EM algorithm
これが EM アルゴリズムです
The third example I'm going to talk about is this
これから説明する 3 番目の例はこれです
The so-called Kippelmeyer Curve
いわゆるキッペルマイヤー曲線
This is two peoples
これは二人の民族です
two peoples
二人の人々
two peoples two statisticians
二人の民族 二人の統計学者
What does this curve do?
この曲線は何をするのでしょうか?
it is going to be estimated
推定されることになります
This kind of curve actually I think
このようなカーブは実際にあると思います
doing if there is this
これがあればやってる
is a biomedical background
生物医学的な背景です
especially the words of the researchers
特に研究者の言葉
may be very familiar
とてもよく知られているかもしれません
especially doctors
特に医者
you may very well be in
あなたはとても得意かもしれません
See such graphics on medical journals
医学雑誌でそのようなグラフィックを参照してください
what is this
これは何ですか
this is one
これは 1 つです
This is a group of patients
こちらは患者さんのグループです
you have to estimate it
それを見積もる必要があります
survival curve
生存曲線
survival rate
生存率
So what about the Y axis?
では、Y軸はどうでしょうか？
represents the survival rate
生存率を表します
Survival rate, so you can see it's 1 at the beginning, right?
生存率なので最初は1であることがわかりますよね？
In the beginning, everyone survived
最初はみんな生き残ってた
Then gradually as time goes on
それから時間が経つにつれて徐々に
Over time it will, the survival rate will
時間の経過とともに生存率は下がります
when you have someone gradually passing away
徐々に亡くなっていく人がいるとき
Your survival rate will keep dropping
生存率は下がり続けるだろう
So what is this district line like?
では、この区線はどのようなものなのでしょうか？
It is to tell you that this group of patients their
この患者グループは彼らの
A situation in which survival rates decrease over time
時間の経過とともに生存率が低下する状況
So doctors often have such zone lines
したがって、医師はしばしばそのようなゾーンラインを持っています
Let's see, for example, the five-year survival rate for cancer
たとえば、がんの5年生存率を見てみましょう。
data like this is very important to them
このようなデータは彼らにとって非常に重要です
A tool that this survival zone line
このサバイバルゾーンラインが実現するツール
In fact, it is not simple at all
実際には全く単純ではありません
so we have to
だから私たちはそうしなければなりません
But the so-called survival rate means
しかし、いわゆる生存率というのは、
For example, he just said this picture
たとえば、彼はちょうどこの写真を言いました
What are the chances that he just lived past 10 months?
彼がちょうど 10 か月生きていた可能性はどれくらいですか?
then you go and see
それから行って見てください
His chances of this his time over 10 months
その可能性は 10 か月以上かかる
You even count, right?
あなたも数えますよね？
But the reality is not so simple
しかし現実はそれほど単純ではありません
because
なぜなら
if you think about it
考えてみれば
if you today
もし今日あなたが
what you want to see today is
今日見たいものは
50 month survival rate
50か月生存率
that may be a lot of people
それは多くの人かもしれない
that is
あれは
That is to say, 50 months is about a few years
つまり、50か月は約数年に相当します
4 years right?
4年ですよね？
4 years
4年
and you
あなたも
You are going to record this result today
今日この結果を記録する予定です
Maybe you're doing a clinical study
もしかしたら臨床研究をしているのかもしれない
right
右
But what?
でも何？
Although you said you want
欲しいって言ったのに
you want to get a 50
50点を取りたいですか
50 months is a survival rate of over 4 years, right?
50ヶ月って4年以上の生存率ですよね？
But maybe you can't wait that long
でも、そんなに長く待てないかもしれない
you can't wait that long
そんなに長く待つことはできません
That means you may have to within 3 years
つまり、3年以内にやらなければならない可能性があります
You will have a statistical result
統計結果が得られます
so it becomes
そうなります
some people if he
彼なら何人かの人々
when he was 3 years old
彼が3歳のとき
he is alive
彼は生きています
You can't see the real age of death of these people
これらの人々の実際の死亡年齢はわかりません
because you can't
できないから
Because some people he will survive longer
彼がもっと長生きする人もいるから
But your observation time is limited
ただし観察時間は限られています
is limited
制限されています
you can't help
あなたは助けることができません
Everyone tracked down his real death
誰もが彼の本当の死を追跡した
So this would result in
したがって、これは次のようになります
Some complexity of our data
データの一部の複雑さ
you're at the end of three years
あなたは3年が終わるところです
so all you know is to say
だからあなたが知っているのはそれだけです
he lived for three years
彼は3年間生きました
but you have no way of knowing
しかしあなたにはそれを知る方法がありません
how long did he really survive
彼は実際どれくらい生きたのか
because after three years
なぜなら3年後だから
You no longer observe this patient
もうこの患者を観察することはありません
Follow up with this patient again
この患者を再度フォローアップする
What about the other side?
反対側はどうですか？
There are some other possibilities
他にもいくつかの可能性があります
Maybe it's not a matter of you not having enough time to observe
観察する時間が足りないという問題ではないのかもしれない
Maybe even this patient
もしかしたらこの患者さんも
He may have been transferred midway.
途中で異動になったのかもしれない。
or he moved
あるいは彼は引っ越した
you will never find him
あなたは彼を決して見つけることはできないでしょう
So maybe at twenty months he
それで、おそらく20か月の時点で、彼は
he is alive and well
彼は元気に生きています
But he moved next
しかし、その後彼は引っ越しました
you won't be able to contact him
あなたは彼に連絡できなくなるでしょう
So what about this kind of person?
では、このような人はどうでしょうか？
also cause
原因にもなる
This complexity in our data
データのこの複雑さ
We are going to do this kind of data
このようなデータを作成します
We call it Sensor Data
私たちはそれをセンサーデータと呼んでいます
Sensor Data
センサーデータ
So how about this kind of Sensor Data
では、このようなセンサーデータはどうでしょうか
in the presence of
の存在下で
to get a correct
正しく理解するために
survival curve survival curve
生存曲線 生存曲線
What about this estimate?
この見積もりはどうでしょうか？
Inference?
推論？
this is a
これは
It's actually not a simple question
実はそれは簡単な質問ではありません
That is also through Kepham and Meyer
それもケファムとマイヤーを通して
Where are the two statisticians?
二人の統計学者はどこにいるのでしょうか？
They discovered the method
彼らはその方法を発見した
So we'll call it now
それでは、今すぐ呼び出します
Kepham-Meyer Curve
ケファム・マイヤー曲線
Or called Proud-Limit Curve
またはプラウド リミット カーブと呼ばれます
So what about the doctor now?
それで、医者は今どうですか？
Although he may only be able to observe
彼はただ観察することしかできないかもしれないが、
one short year short three years
1年短い 3年短い
Or that although his patients may
あるいは、彼の患者はそうかもしれないが、
some will be lost in the middle
一部は途中で失われます
will not see these patients
これらの患者を診ることはないだろう
won't find these patients
これらの患者は見つからないだろう
but it doesn't matter
でもそれは関係ない
he can still
彼はまだできる
According to the collected
集めたものによると、
whether complete data
完全なデータかどうか
Or these so-called Sensor Data
またはこれらのいわゆるセンサーデータ
he can
彼はできる
to get one of these patients
これらの患者の一人を捕まえるために
This curve of survival
この生存曲線
So this is the Gibbon-Mine Curve
これがギボン・マイン・カーブです
good
良い
Okay, so is there any problem with the above?
さて、上記について何か問題はありますか？
So my background has taken an hour
私の背景には1時間かかりました
So I only have 30 minutes left for my example
したがって、この例の残り時間は 30 分しかありません
good
良い
Well, that's our topic today
さて、それが今日のテーマです
that is
あれは
What the statistics are doing I used two examples
統計が何をしているのか 2 つの例を使用しました
What I must tell you is that
私があなたに言わなければならないことは、
Of course statistics are doing too much
もちろん統計はやりすぎだ
The examples I can give are very limited to my own
私が挙げられる例は私自身のものに非常に限られています
very limited experience
非常に限られた経験
So I'm sure you can learn from other statisticians
したがって、他の統計学者から学ぶことができると確信しています
get more interesting examples
もっと興味深い例を入手する
That
それか
My first example is earthquake risk assessment
最初の例は地震リスク評価です
This is actually me
これは実は私です
i used to
以前はよく＿＿していた
When I first became an actor, I told the world
初めて俳優になったとき、私は世界にこう言いました
A researcher Cai Sovereign, Teacher Cai
研究者、蔡ソブリン、蔡先生
A study we collaborated on
私たちが協力して行った研究
That is to continue with this
それはこれを続けるということです
Dr. Zhao from the National Earthquake Engineering Research Center
国立地震工学研究センターのZhao博士
Zhao Chuxian Dr. Zhao
趙秋仙 趙博士
We continue our research on this
私たちはこれについて研究を続けています
Then I think everyone knows about earthquakes
それから、地震については誰もが知っていると思います
This one is of course for us
これはもちろん私たちのためのものです
big threat in taiwan
台湾における大きな脅威
Then this is the earthquakes that happened in the past few years
それから、これがここ数年に起きた地震です
The location of the repression and the larger the circles represent
抑圧の位置と円が大きいほど表されます。
The scale of its earthquake is bigger
地震の規模はさらに大きくなる
well then
じゃあ
Earthquake Engineers One Thing They're Important
地震技術者が重要なことは 1 つ
is to construct these earthquake-measured
地震によって測定されたものを構築することです
The so-called surface acceleration is when the earthquake shakes
いわゆる表面加速度は、地震が揺れるときのことです。
They will have an instrument measuring the acceleration of our surface
彼らは私たちの表面の加速度を測定する装置を持っているでしょう
It is very important for earthquake engineers to establish this
地震技術者にとってこれを確立することは非常に重要です。
this surface acceleration
この地面の加速度
This is the skewed axis of the graph. Surface acceleration.
これはグラフの歪んだ軸、つまり表面加速度です。
With the crackdown distance away from me this car
私から取り締まり距離が離れているので、この車は
The distance from my measuring station to my location
測定ステーションから現在地までの距離
one of
的一個
Attenuation situation
減衰状況
We know that if the distance
距離が離れていれば
If the suppression is farther away, of course the surface acceleration will be smaller
抑制が遠ければ当然表面加速度は小さくなります
Because the repression will be less
弾圧が少なくなるから
Right, the closer you are, the greater the suppression
そう、近づくほど抑圧は大きくなる
So the surface acceleration will be greater
したがって、表面加速度は大きくなります
there is another one
もう一つあります
The factor that affects this surface acceleration is of course the size of the earthquake.
この表面加速度に影響を与える要因は、言うまでもなく地震の規模です。
The scale is extremely extreme earthquake
規模は極めて巨大な地震
so
それで
It is important for earthquake engineers to construct this so-called
地震技術者にとって、いわゆるこの構造を構築することが重要です。
Attenuation Model of Surface Acceleration
表面加速度の減衰モデル
According to this model, he can go
このモデルによると、彼は行くことができます
predict
予測する
These data are from these points are this
これらのデータはこれらのポイントからのものです
These so-called seismic strong and low motion stations
これらのいわゆる強震観測点および低震動観測点
The actual data measured by surface acceleration
表面加速度による実測データ
That
それか
One of their very important things is to construct from these data
彼らにとって非常に重要なことの 1 つは、これらのデータから構築することです
to predict a place
場所を予測する
For example, a nuclear power plant
たとえば、原子力発電所
or a school
または学校
or a subway station
または地下鉄の駅
That location is at a certain suppression distance
その場所は特定の制圧距離にあります
and below the scale of an earthquake
しかも地震規模以下
how much ground acceleration will it have
どれくらいの対地加速度があるだろうか
Build engineering staff from here
ここからエンジニアリングスタッフを構築します
to build a nuclear power plant
原子力発電所を建設する
Or to build a subway station
あるいは地下鉄の駅を建設する
Or the engineers who want to build the school
または学校を建設したいエンジニア
to design their building
あなたは彼らの建物を設計することができます
How strong is the seismic coefficient
耐震係数はどのくらいですか
or safety factor
または安全率
So this is a very important job for them
ですから、これは彼らにとって非常に重要な仕事です
this is what they call
これを彼らはそう呼んでいます
Ground motion attenuation model or surface acceleration attenuation model
地震動減衰モデルまたは表面加速度減衰モデル
What about this curve?
この曲線はどうでしょうか？
is their mathematical model
彼らの数学的モデルです
The mathematical model they constructed
彼らが構築した数学モデル
but what about the blue dot
しかし、青い点はどうでしょうか
is the actual measured data
実際の測定データです
So from here you can see that
ここからはそれがわかります
What about the data?
データはどうですか？
Compared to this model
このモデルと比較すると
still showed a very large
まだ非常に大きなものを示しました
Uncertainty right?
不確実性はありますよね？
That is to say, if you want to use this
つまり、これを使用したい場合は、
this model
このモデル
This is actually a so-called statistical regression model
これは実際にはいわゆる統計的回帰モデルです
From such a regression model to predict
このような回帰モデルから予測する
an actual earthquake
実際の地震
the ground acceleration it causes
それが引き起こす地面の加速度
there is still a lot of uncertainty
まだ不確実性がたくさんあります
There is still a big error, right?
まだ大きな間違いがありますよね？
great degree of change
大きな変化
So at first
だから最初は
As I just said, we have a lot of these book exhibitions in Taiwan
先ほども言いましたが、台湾ではこういった書籍の展示会がたくさん開催されています。
Most of these book exhibitions are set up in primary and secondary schools.
こうした書籍展示会のほとんどは小中学校で開催されます。
When an earthquake occurs there are measurements of surface acceleration
地震が発生すると、表面加速度が測定されます。
These are the blue dots we just had
これらは先ほどの青い点です
So the question we now have to ask is
したがって、私たちが今尋ねなければならない質問は次のとおりです
is there any way we can say
何か言える方法はありますか？
in just this
たったこれだけで
a model, right?
モデルですよね？
Then there's an error in the actual ground acceleration, right?
そうすると実際の対地加速度には誤差が生じますよね？
Is there any way for us to further reduce this error?
この誤差をさらに減らす方法はあるでしょうか?
how to shrink it
どうやって縮めるか
That is to say, is there any way for us to convert this error
つまり、このエラーを解決する方法はありますか?
take this uncertainty
この不確実性を置いて
uncertainty
不確実性
further broken down into
さらに細分化すると
this
これ
this is just now
これは今だけです
The mathematical model of this is to consider the scale of the earthquake
これの数学的モデルは地震の規模を考慮することです
After the distance from Zhenyang
鎮陽から離れた後
model, but the latter is full of errors
モデルですが、後者はエラーがいっぱいです
That
それか
The decomposition of this error we would hope for
私たちが望むこのエラーの分解
It is hoped that further decomposition into
さらに分解されることが期待されます。
One is the error caused by different earthquakes
1つは、異なる地震によって引き起こされる誤差です。
So that is to say, this part of the error can be determined by
つまり、エラーのこの部分は次のように判断できます。
explained by the characteristics of the earthquake itself
地震自体の特徴によって説明される
What about the other component of the error?
エラーの他の要素についてはどうですか?
Because of the nature of the station and the location itself
駅の性質上、立地自体の都合上、
caused by
所造成的
So this error is different locations
したがって、このエラーは別の場所にあります
Because some of it may be a basin
一部は盆地かもしれないので
Some may be on this hard rock
この固い岩の上にいる人もいるかもしれない
some may be in the sand
いくつかは砂の中にあるかもしれない
So it will cause its surface acceleration to be different
したがって、表面加速度が異なります
So this part of the error?
では、この部分がエラーなのでしょうか？
Because of
なぜなら
This part of this uncertainty
この不確実性のこの部分
is due to the characteristics between different locations
異なる場所間の特性によるものです
this change
この変化
this fairwayation
このフェアウェイ
what about the end
最後はどうですか
The rest of this is that we can't have the properties of the earthquake itself
残りの部分は、地震そのものの特性を得ることができないということです。
or this error explained by the geological properties of the site itself
あるいは、この誤差はその場所自体の地質学的性質によって説明される
so what
だから何
all we have to do is say
私たちがしなければならないのは言うことだけです
Mr. Cai
蔡さん
when we come to discuss this issue
私たちがこの問題について話し合うとき
we just wanted to say
私たちはただ言いたかっただけです
Is there a way outside of the original regression model
元の回帰モデルから抜け出す方法はありますか
take this further
これをさらに進めてください
regression model
回帰モデル
The remaining error
残ったエラー
remaining uncertainty
残る不確実性
take this further
これをさらに進めてください
Uncertainty caused by the earthquake itself
地震そのものによる不確実性
take it
それを取る
jump out
飛び出す
and because the location itself
それから場所自体のせいで
Uncertainty caused by the properties of Single it out
Single it out の特性によって生じる不確実性
In this case, when we make predictions later,
この場合、後で予測すると、
According to the characteristics of the earthquake itself,
地震そのものの特徴からすると、
and the characteristics of the place itself
そしてその場所自体の特徴
Further send this error to it
このエラーをさらに送信します
So a more accurate error can be obtained
より正確な誤差が得られるようになります
more accurate predictions
より正確な予測
So here's our question
そこで質問です
our problem our approach
私たちの問題 私たちのアプローチ
In fact, using our statistics
実際、私たちの統計を使用すると、
A very common tool in statistics
統計における非常に一般的なツール
is a so-called mixed effects model
いわゆる混合効果モデルです
or a random effects model
または変量効果モデル
We add the original regression model to
元の回帰モデルを追加します
Due to the random effect caused by the earthquake
地震によるランダムな影響により
and because of different locations
そして場所が違うので
Random effects caused by different strategies
さまざまな戦略によって引き起こされるランダムな効果
We all assume that this water accumulation effect is a normal distribution
私たちは皆、この水の蓄積効果が正規分布であると仮定しています。
is the normal distribution of the central limit theorem we just saw
先ほど見た中心極限定理の正規分布です
So what we want to know now is this normal distribution
そこで今知りたいのはこの正規分布です
Just mentioned its width, how much does it change
幅について言及しましたが、どれくらい変わりますか
Because of this change, such as the effect of an earthquake
地震の影響などによるこの変化により
The variation and width of its normal distribution can tell me
正規分布のばらつきと幅からわかること
That is, because of the earthquake, this can be explained
つまり、地震のせいで説明がつくのです。
How much is this variation of farration How much is this ingredient
この遠心度の変化はいくらですか、この成分はいくらですか
Then this location its normal distribution its this
次に、この位置の正規分布はこれです
mutate it to this width
この幅に変更します
it tells me that because of the location
場所のせいでそう言われます
What is the extent of the change
変化の程度はどの程度ですか
and finally this
そして最後にこれ
not explained by any reason that we know of
私たちが知っているいかなる理由によっても説明されていません
this kind
この種
How much does the error vary
誤差はどれくらい変わるのか
so
それで
This is the parameter we want to know
これが知りたいパラメータです
Known parameters
既知のパラメータ
So we just pass
だから私たちはただ通り過ぎるだけです
EM just said
EMは今言いました
algorithm
演算法
to perform this calculation on this model
このモデルでこの計算を実行するには
Calculation
計算
So we also have the so-called E-STEP
いわゆるE-STEPもあります
Follow M-STEP
エムステップをフォローする
E-STEP is to calculate
E-STEPは計算することです
the parts of us that don't see
私たちの見えない部分
those papers
それらの書類
what's the missing part
足りない部分は何ですか
That's what I just said
それが私が今言ったことです
earthquake
地震
the effect of
の効果
Place
場所
Why can't I see it? It's because
なぜ見えないのか?それは、
he has been with
彼は一緒にいた
Just now, these things in front of this are all mixed together.
今、この前にあるものが全部ごちゃ混ぜになってます。
And the last error all mixed up
そして最後のエラーはすべて混同されています
We only saw this Y at the end
最後にこのYしか見られなかった
Y is our surface acceleration
Y は表面加速度です
So we have no way of actually seeing
したがって、実際に見る方法はありません
Effects due to seismic properties
耐震性による影響
Effects on Surface Acceleration
表面加速への影響
and the characteristics of the place
そしてその場所の特徴
So these are the parts that we don't see
つまり、これらは私たちには見えない部分です
So we use Y
したがって、Yを使用します
replace it then max
それを交換してから最大にします
then this
それからこれ
always
いつも
overlapping tape finally converges it
テープを重ねてようやく収束
so
それで
I skipped all of these
これらすべてをスキップしました
these are mathematical formulas
これらは数式です
i just skip it
私はそれをスキップするだけです
so in the end
それで結局のところ
We can get these parameters
これらのパラメータを取得できます
components of these errors
これらのエラーの構成要素
These parameters of the composition of these changes
これらの変更を構成するパラメータ
these parameters
これらのパラメータ
Then we can also get the predicted value of the surface acceleration
そうすれば、表面加速度の予測値も取得できます。
Bring these parameters into
これらのパラメータを
bring in
持ち込む
then go get it
それから取りに行きます
95% confidence interval or prediction interval
95% 信頼区間または予測区間
Just like the poll example just now
先ほどのアンケートの例のように
We can construct its prediction interval
その予測区間を構築できます
so what
だから何
we use this
私たちはこれを使います
period ratio
期間多比
this
これ
just these stations
これらの駅だけ
The resulting data
結果として得られるデータ
In fact, most of these stations are operated by us
実際、これらの駅のほとんどは私たちが運営しています
The Central Weather Service and this us
中央気象局と私たち
Academia Sinica's Institute of Earth Sciences
中央研究院地球科学研究所
they established
彼らは設立した
so
それで
These are the earthquakes just mentioned
これらは今言及した地震です
Those ones
それらです
Those Effects
それらの効果
Those Earthquakes
あの地震
those
それらの
These are those Sites those side stations
これらはそれらのサイトです、それらのサイドステーションです
so this is us
これが私たちです
The previous regression model
以前の回帰モデル
M is the magnitude of the earthquake
M は地震のマグニチュードです
R is the distance from this point to the center
R はこの点から中心までの距離です
So this is a common one for their earthquake engineering
つまり、これは彼らの地震工学では一般的なものです
What the regression model looks like
回帰モデルはどのようなものなのか
Then we have to do more than just this regression model
その場合、この回帰モデル以上のことを行う必要があります。
what about us
私たちについてはどうですか
I also hope that this is the parameter value of this model
これがこのモデルのパラメータ値であることを願っています
We use the EM algorithm
EMアルゴリズムを使用します
The resulting parameter value
結果のパラメータ値
and the one with its central limit theorem
とその中心極限定理
the one with the normal distribution
正規分布のもの
that
それか
the width of that change
その変化の幅
Error that standard arrow
標準の矢印のエラー
that standard
その基準
good
良い
that this is that
これはそれです
just said
今言いました
We have
我々は持っています
different earthquakes
さまざまな地震
Caused change This parameter Amount of change
原因となる変化 このパラメータ 変化量
The amount of variation caused by different locations
場所の違いによる変動量
Is there any way to explain it by all known causes
既知の原因をすべて説明する方法はありますか
The remaining changes, these uncertainties
残りの変化、これらの不確実性
So is the estimate of the parameter of these parameters
これらのパラメータの推定値も同様です
the values ​​of the parameters and their
パラメータの値とその
The degree of variation produced by sampling error
サンプリング誤差によるばらつきの程度
its standard
その標準
These are obtained by the EM algorithm
これらは EM アルゴリズムによって取得されます
Then this, Vice President Zhou just said
それから、周副主席はこう言いました。
Can we have such a model to know
そのようなモデルを知ることができますか
Which side is safer and which side is less safe, right?
どちらの側がより安全で、どちらの側が安全ではないでしょうか？
So this is an example that says
これは次のような例です
Because we can get the effect of the location, right?
場所の効果が得られるからですよね？
The impact of this site just now
今のこのサイトの影響
So here are some different tactics
そこで、いくつかの異なる戦術を紹介します
This is Yilan
ここは宜蘭です
Hualien's Taipei's Kaohsiung's Yilan's
花蓮の台北の高雄の宜蘭の
so you can see it's slightly safer in this place
この場所は少し安全だということがわかります
A little bit because its surface acceleration will deduct a little bit
表面加速度が少し差し引かれるので少しだけ
right
右
This place will also deduct a little, then this place will add
ここも少し差し引いて、ここは追加します
plus a little plus a little more than average
プラス少しプラス平均より少しプラス
just add a little bit, right?
少しだけ加えるだけですよね？
so this is
それでこれは
Predict this surface acceleration from the location
位置に基づいてこの地面の加速度を予測します
An example is our original purpose
例は私たちの本来の目的です
At the beginning we just hoped that in
初めはただそれを望んでいた
above the original regression model, can we go further
元の回帰モデルを超えていますが、さらに進めることはできますか?
Pick out the effects of location Pick out the effects of earthquakes
場所の影響を抽出する 地震の影響を抽出する
This way we can get more accurate predictions
こうすることで、より正確な予測を得ることができます
Well, this one is based on different earthquakes
さて、これはさまざまな地震に基づいています
Pick out its effects and this one is
その効果をピックアップしてみると、これは
921 This Extremely Large Earthquake
921 この超巨大地震
Happened in 1999
1999年に起こった
The 921 earthquake
921 地震
So this is what I just explained
それで、これが今私が説明したことです
In fact, after you take the special factor of location into consideration
実際、場所という特殊な要素を考慮すると、
What if you use this EM algorithm to make a prediction?
この EM アルゴリズムを使用して予測を行うとどうなるでしょうか?
You are actually better than the original regression model they used that did not take into account the location.
実際、場所を考慮せずに使用した元の回帰モデルよりも優れています。
When you construct its ninety-five stars to interval
95個の星を間隔をあけて組み立てるとき
Realization This diagram may not be clear
認識 この図は明確ではないかもしれません
Achieving this is its range
これを達成することがその範囲です
You can see that for this strategy in Taipei
台北のこの戦略ではそれがわかります。
Well, actually, it turns out that this didn’t take into account the location.
実は、これは場所を考慮していないことが判明しました。
What about the prediction interval at the 95-star level?
95 つ星レベルの予測間隔はどうなるでしょうか?
doesn't cover ground acceleration at this location at all
この場所での地面加速度はまったくカバーされていません
Right, this range is here
そう、この範囲はここです
But it is not included in the strategy of Taipei
しかし、それは台北の戦略には含まれていない
is not covered by this prediction interval of the ninety-five
95 というこの予測間隔の対象にはなりません。
But if you consider the site conditions of the station itself
しかし、駅自体の敷地条件を考慮すると、
The interval you construct will be this dotted line
構築する間隔はこの点線になります
So you can see that it will better cover the surface acceleration of this location
したがって、この場所の表面加速度をより適切にカバーできることがわかります。
The same is true for a station in Kaohsiung
高雄の駅も同様です
This location of this station is here
この駅の場所はここです
This its PGA surface acceleration is here
これは PGA 表面の加速がここにあります
This is the 95% prediction interval constructed based on the characteristics of the site
これは、サイトの特性に基づいて構築された 95% 予測区間です。
That realization is this interval
その気づきがこのインターバル
Implementations also include live without taking into account
実装には考慮しないライブも含まれます
Those who did not consider the characteristics of this site are also included in the station in Kaohsiung
このサイトの特性を考慮していない人も高雄の駅に含まれます
But its location is on the edge
しかし、その場所は端にあります
good
良い
The EM algorithm just mentioned is a very general method
先ほど述べた EM アルゴリズムは非常に一般的な方法です
So in fact, this earthquake engineering expert
実は、この地震工学の専門家は、
they hope that means
彼らはそれが意味することを望んでいる
if my
もし私の
What if the effect of my earthquake is
私の地震の影響がもし
Just this model is
ただこのモデルは
The effect of an earthquake is the same
地震の影響も同じです
all earthquakes
すべての地震
effect is the same
効果は同じです
That
それか
Earthquake engineers asked
地震専門家が尋ねた
Then if the effect of my earthquake will follow
それで私の地震の影響が続くなら
Will it be different in size?
大きさも違うのでしょうか？
I think this is a very reasonable question
これは非常に合理的な質問だと思います
Then we can easily
そうすれば簡単にできます
Take this EM algorithm slightly
この EM アルゴリズムを少し取り上げてみましょう
rewrite it
書き直す
we can go and calculate
行って計算してみましょう
Above is my first example
上記は私の最初の例です
My first example to summarize
要約する最初の例
that is
あれは
Now we have very, very many in Taiwan
今では台湾にとてもたくさんの人がいます
They now have a very
彼らは今、とても
have a database
データベースを持っている
So I think you can apply with them if you want to use it.
なので、使いたい場合は一緒に申し込んでもいいと思います。
That
それか
In fact, the statistical regression has been
実際、統計的回帰は次のようになります。
model approach has been used for this surface acceleration
この表面加速にはモデルアプローチが使用されています
The construction of the decay model
減衰モデルの構築
From which to evaluate the so-called Size Mihaasang
いわゆるサイズミハサンを評価するための基準
earthquake risk
地震の危険性
But we can use more
しかし、もっと活用できる
A more refined statistical model
より洗練された統計モデル
For example, as shown here
たとえば、ここに示すように
The so-called mixed-effects or random-effects model
いわゆる混合効果または変量効果モデル
We can further take the original regression model inside
元の回帰モデルをさらに内部に取り込むことができます
What about the variable part?
可変部分についてはどうですか？
Further according to different sources
さらにさまざまな情報源によると
different ingredients
さまざまな成分
For example from Earthquake itself
たとえば、地震自体から
from Sight itself
視覚そのものから
to further disassemble
さらに分解する
get more accurate forecasts
より正確な予測を得る
statistical algorithm
統計アルゴリズム
like 1M algorithm
1Mアルゴリズムのような
can help us do this
私たちがこれを行うのを手伝ってくれる
Statistical Proxy Sample Theory
統計的代理サンプル理論
You can also help us further
さらに私たちを助けてくれる
Evaluate the resulting model on the data
データに基づいて結果のモデルを評価する
its error how much its uncertainty
その誤差はどの程度不確実性があるのか
So this is my first example
これが私の最初の例です
Thanks
ありがとう
Well, the second example is to follow the popular big data
2 番目の例は、人気のあるビッグデータに従うことです。
hope there is a little connection
少しでもつながりがあることを願っています
So here's an example of integration of different databases
ここでは、さまざまなデータベースの統合例を示します。
Now because, a lot of databases, a lot of this database
なぜなら、たくさんのデータベース、このデータベースの多くが
It's all there for everyone to use, whether it's a government agency.
政府機関かどうかにかかわらず、誰もが使用できるものはすべてあります。
or a private institution
または民間機関
Slowly now because of the trend of big data, there may be more and more such data
今はビッグデータのトレンドにより、徐々にそのようなデータが増えていくかもしれません
What about this data? Its advantage is that it is usually very large.
このデータはどうでしょうか? その利点は、通常、データが非常に大きいことです。
A large amount because it can be very cumulative for very many people
非常に多くの人にとって非常に累積される可能性があるため、多額の金額
Daily life, for example, it is called UBIKE, right?
日常生活、例えばUBIKEって言いますよね？
Its records, or our health care records, our doctor's records
その記録、あるいは私たちの医療記録、医師の記録
so everyone
だからみんな
A large amount of data accumulated for a long time every day
毎日長期間にわたって蓄積される大量のデータ
So its advantage is that it has a large amount
なので量が多いのが利点です
but on the other hand
しかし一方で
It has the disadvantage that
という欠点があります
Because it wasn't meant for a real one
本物に向けたものではないから
Collected for the purpose of measuring something in detail
何かを詳細に測定する目的で収集される
So what about its data?
では、そのデータはどうなるのでしょうか?
The quality may be rough
品質が荒いかもしれません
There may be a lot of errors, right?
間違いがたくさんあるかもしれませんね？
what about the other
もう一方はどうですか
even
平
For example, like the health insurance database
たとえば、健康保険データベースのような
Anyone who has analyzed the health insurance database knows that
健康保険データベースを分析したことのある人なら誰でも知っています。
Actually because
実は、なぜなら
Currently because of
現在の理由は、
The so-called capital
所謂的各資
so-called personal privacy
いわゆる個人のプライバシー
is guaranteed
保証されています
so
それで
you can't just say
ただ言うことはできません
you can't get these
これらは入手できません
Although it has large data
データが大きいにもかかわらず
But you can't get its personal data
ただし、個人データを取得することはできません
Our statistical analysis needs it for a long time
私たちの統計分析には長い間それが必要でした
individual data personal data
individual data 個人的資料
One by one we can analyze
一つ一つ分析できる
but now
でも今
it allows you to analyze
分析できるようになります
But it doesn't let you take this profile back
ただし、このプロファイルを元に戻すことはできません
You can only take the results of the analysis
分析結果のみを取得できます
That is, Somber is the taste is
つまり、くすんだ味は
These sufficient statistics bring back
これらの十分な統計により、
Like the so-called we went to the Ministry of Health and Welfare
いわゆる厚生省に行きました
value-added center
付加価値センター
That's it
それでおしまい
you can go in and sit at its computer
中に入ってコンピューターの前に座ることができます
To analyze the health insurance database
健康保険データベースを分析するには
but when you go
でも行くときは
It can only bring out your analysis results
分析結果のみを引き出すことができます
You can't bring the data out
データの持ち出しはできない
good
良い
but on the other hand
しかし一方で
A person or some may exist now
人または何人かが現在存在している可能性があります
existing some
既存のいくつかの
For other databases it might be
他のデータベースの場合は、次のようになります。
There are finer
もっと細かいものもあります
measured to some
ある程度測定した
the data you want
欲しいデータ
These databases may exist or
これらのデータベースは存在する可能性があります。あるいは、
yourself if
もしあなた自身
If there is such a data to be collected
収集すべきそのようなデータがある場合
That's the kind of information you have on hand.
それがあなたが手元に持っている情報です。
right
右
So a natural question is to say
したがって、当然の疑問は次のようになります。
Here you have some very
ここにいくつかの非常に優れたものがあります
detailed measurement data
詳細な測定データ
But because it's finely measured
でも細かく測ってるので
so its amount
それでその量
maybe not too big
大きすぎないかもしれない
right
右
because
なぜなら
Fine measurements cost a lot of money
精密な測定には多額の費用がかかります
right
右
you can't measure too many people
あまりにも多くの人を測定することはできません
too many people
あまりにも多くの人々
So you have a profile like this
このようなプロフィールがあります
is it possible to follow
フォローすることは可能ですか？
the one above
上のもの
this huge database
この巨大なデータベース
it's big
それは大きいです
a lot of it
それがたくさん
but a little rough
でも少し荒い
How can you combine these two
この 2 つをどのように組み合わせることができますか
database combined
結合されたデータベース
so this is us
これが私たちです
question to ask
尋ねるべき質問
Okay, so our motivation is to say
さて、私たちの動機は次のとおりです。
There is a doctor who has one at hand
手元に持っている医者がいます
National Health Interview Survey
国民健康面接調査
That this is 2005
これが2005年だということ
this is
これは
National Institutes of Health in Taiwan
台湾の国立衛生研究所
and the National Health Service
および国民保健サービス
what they
彼らは何を
an interview survey
インタビュー調査
This is a very detailed visit
とても詳しい訪問です
More than 20,000 residents of Taiwan
台湾在住者は2万人以上
very carefully
非常に慎重に
Ask them what diseases they have
どのような病気にかかっているのかを尋ねます
and then include their diet
次に食事も含めます
their living habits
彼らの生活習慣
their smoking and drinking
彼らの喫煙と飲酒
so
それで
There is such a database
こんなデータベースあるんですね
This is a very detailed database
これは非常に詳細なデータベースです
but this database
しかし、それはこのデータベースです
Relatively speaking, the amount is not that large
比較的金額的にはそこまで多くないですが、
That's all, more than 20,000 people
それだけで2万人以上
What the doctor wants to analyze is
医師が分析したいのは
because he found
彼が見つけたから
patients with herpes zoster
帯状疱疹の患者
Herpes zoster I don't know everyone
帯状疱疹 みんな知らない
Do you know what kind of disease this is?
これはどんな病気か知っていますか？
It's a disease of the immune system
免疫系の病気です
he is in pain
彼は苦しんでいます
It's a sharp pain
非常痛
If you have this rash
この発疹がある場合
it will be very painful
とても痛いでしょう
you must see a doctor
医者に診てもらう必要があります
will definitely see a doctor
必ず医者に診てもらいます
Then the doctor found
そこで医者が見つけたのが、
Many people who get shingles with this shingles
この帯状疱疹は多くの人が帯状疱疹になります
He also has COPD
彼もCOPDを患っている
COPD
COPD
so he just watched
だから彼はただ見ていた
Are these two diseases related?
これら 2 つの病気は関連していますか?
do you have chronic obstructive pulmonary disease
慢性閉塞性肺疾患がありますか
prone to herpes zoster
帯状疱疹になりやすい
that's in this
それはこの中にあります
If he wants to discuss such issues
彼がそのような問題について話し合いたい場合
he has a lot
彼はたくさん持っています
Other variables to consider
考慮すべきその他の変数
for example
例えば
There are a lot more
他にもたくさんあります
other comorbidities
他の併存疾患
comorbidity
併存疾患
such as high blood pressure, diabetes
高血圧、糖尿病など
These will be accompanied by both levels of water
これらには両方のレベルの水が伴います
together with the
と一緒に
Then there is smoking and drinking
あとは喫煙と飲酒です
especially smoking
特に喫煙
because
なぜなら
Many people with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease are
慢性閉塞性肺疾患を患っている人の多くは、
Primers
プライマー
I mean smoke a lot
つまり、たくさん吸うのです
It is easy for smokers to get
喫煙者にとっては入手しやすい
Ribbon foam pillow
リボンフォームピロー
so
それで
smoking is an important
喫煙は重要です
this
これ
Factors that must be included in the analysis
分析に含める必要がある要素
and drinking
そして飲酒
So these data can be found in
したがって、これらのデータは次の場所にあります。
National Health Survey in French
フランス語による国民健康調査
This is a very detailed investigation
非常に詳細な調査です
But it's not that big
でもそんなに大きくないよ
So the doctor thought
そこで医師は考えました
Then can I use the health insurance database?
では、健康保険データベースは利用できるのでしょうか？
Because now the health insurance database
因為現在健保資料庫
very hot right now
今とても暑いです
The health insurance database is missing.
健康保険データベースがありません。
smoking and drinking
喫煙と飲酒
no smoking and drinking
喫煙と飲酒は禁止です
data
データ
how about
どうですか
In this way, the health insurance database lacks smoking and drinking
このようにして、健康保険データベースには喫煙と飲酒が存在しません。
The result of such an analysis we call
このような分析の結果を私たちは「
one reduce model one
一個reduce model 一個
A scaled down model because it's less smoking and less drinking, right?
減煙、減酒だから縮小モデルですよね？
So what about the results? It’s the same as your National Health Interview Survey.
では、結果はどうなるのでしょうか?それは国民健康面接調査と同じです。
fine this
これでいいです
results combined
結合された結果
ok so here it is
はい、それではこちらです
There are some
幾つかある
a little symbol
小さなシンボル
YX stands for Y
YXはYの略です
It's ours. This one we're going to see is
それは私たちのものです。私たちがこれから見るのはこれです
Ribbon foam pillow
リボンフォームピロー
X is
Xは
Do you have chronic obstructive pulmonary disease and other comorbid diseases?
慢性閉塞性肺疾患および他の併存疾患がありますか
But what we are talking about now is that the data is obtained from external data, which is the so-called health insurance database.
しかし、私たちが今話しているのは、そのデータが外部データ、いわゆる健康保険データベースから取得されるということです。
A large database gets
大規模なデータベースは、
So it's missing some other variables
したがって、他の変数がいくつか欠落しています
such as smoking and drinking
喫煙や飲酒など
that's okay
大丈夫
We use this simplified model
この単純化されたモデルを使用します
reduced model
縮小モデル
we get a final
決勝戦を勝ち取る
Summary
まとめ
A Summary's TASY
一個Summary's TASY
Let's say Said
サイードと言いましょう
That's because the health insurance database
それは、健康保険データベースがあるためです。
Can't take its personal information directly
個人情報を直接取得することはできません
So we can only use this Summary's TASY
したがって、この概要の T​​ASY のみを使用できます。
It describes the relationship between Y and X
Y と X の関係を説明します。
Then it is more precise
それならもっと正確だよ
Our name is Internal Data
私たちの名前は内部データです
In addition to Y and X
YとXに加えて
it also has z
zもあります
some more details
もう少し詳しく
such as smoking and drinking
喫煙や飲酒など
So if you analyze Y X Z
Y X Z を分析すると
integrated analysis
統合分析
A Summary of what you can get
入手できるものの概要
Summary is Beta
概要はベータ版です
Beta
ベータ
The main purpose of statistical inference
統計的推論の主な目的
So how do we combine the two together?
では、この 2 つをどのように組み合わせるのでしょうか?
How to combine beta and seta
ベータとセタを組み合わせる方法
One is the lack of some data
1つはデータが不足していることです
It is a summary of what we call the reduce model
これは、reduce モデルと呼ばれるものの概要です。
One is the summary beta of the complete information
1 つは完全な情報の概要ベータ版です
How do these two fit together?
この 2 つはどのように組み合わされますか?
In fact, it is very simple, we just use the law of large numbers
実際、それは非常に簡単で、大数の法則を使用するだけです。
Because according to the law of large numbers
大数の法則によると
This seta this summary statistic
これはこの概要統計を設定します
it will approach this
これに近づくだろう
The real value of this group
このグループの真価
And the real value of the group will be related to beta
そしてグループの本当の価値はベータに関係します
Because according to one of our probability theory
なぜなら、私たちの確率論の 1 つによれば、
The simplest formula is called total probability
最も単純な式は合計確率と呼ばれます
The law of total probability, right?
全確率の法則ですよね？
The law of total probability tells us
全確率の法則が教えてくれるのは、
total probability tells us
合計確率が教えてくれる
total probability is
合計確率は
Conditional probability multiplied by marginal probability
条件付き確率と周辺確率の積
right
右
So we are based on this simple one
したがって、私たちはこの単純なものに基づいています
Law of Large Numbers and Total Product Rate
大数の法則と総積率
we can go build
私たちは建設に行くことができます
The relationship between β and θ
βとθの関係
So if you go through the health insurance database now
それでは、今健康保険データベースを調べてみると、
You already know the words θ
θという言葉はもう知っていますね
It represents β to some extent
ある程度βを表す
also satisfy a relationship history
交際歴も満たしている
So at this time our statistical inference
したがって、現時点での統計的推論は
We just wanted statistical inference
統計的推論が欲しかっただけです
The pursuit of process optimization, right?
プロセス最適化の追求ですよね？
So when we require the maximum value of the target content
したがって、ターゲットコンテンツの最大値が必要な場合、
We are no longer just the original maximum.
私たちはもはや単なる元の最大値ではありません。
We also add that because of the external data
外部データのため、それも付け加えておきます
message to me
私へのメッセージ
a history of our relationship
私たちの関係の歴史
So this is the use of
したがって、これは次の使用法です
We are in the Elementary Wikipedia
私たちは初級ウィキペディアにいます
Learned method of Lockrange Multi-Prior
Lockrange Multi-Prior の学習方法
that is, with restrictions
つまり制限付き
Let us seek the optimization of an objective content
客観的なコンテンツの最適化を目指しましょう
So we just use this simple trick
そこで、この簡単なトリックを使用するだけです
We can combine external data with internal data
外部データと内部データを組み合わせることができます
then we can also get
そうすれば私たちも得ることができます
The central limit theorem of such statistical inferences
このような統計的推論の中心極限定理
That is, it varies with sampling
つまり、サンプリングによって異なります
Its changes still obey a normal law
その変化は依然として通常の法則に従っています
And the width of the normal and its variation
法線の幅とそのバリエーション
can be calculated by the formula
という式で計算できます
and we found
そして私たちは見つけました
The width of this normal distribution and its variation must be greater than
この正規分布の幅とその変動は、次の値より大きくなければなりません。
Its error, the sampling error, must be greater than
その誤差、つまりサンプリング誤差は、次の値より大きくなければなりません。
You only use your original Internal Data
元の内部データのみを使用します
So it means that you use these additional data
つまり、これらの追加データを使用することになります
use these health care databases use these external data
これらの医療データベースを使用する これらの外部データを使用する
is helpful
役に立ちます
It reduces your sampling error
サンプリングエラーを軽減します
ok so
わかりました、それで
Another one we can combine with internal data
内部データと組み合わせることができるもう 1 つの方法
methods with external data
外部データを使用したメソッド
Also using the central limit theorem
中心極限定理も使う
We use the bivariate normality relationship
二変量正規性関係を使用します
You can build this β and θ
このβとθを構築できます
Remember that β is the parameter of our exact model
β は正確なモデルのパラメータであることを思い出してください。
θ is our external data
θ は外部データです
Compare Simplify compares the parameters of the reduced model
Compare Simplify は、縮小モデルのパラメータを比較します。
You use a central limit theorem
中心極限定理を使用します
Using the relationship of bivariate normal distribution
二変量正規分布の関係を利用する
It is also possible to construct the relationship between these two parameters
これら 2 つのパラメータ間の関係を構築することもできます。
This is also a way
これも一つの方法です
You can combine internal data with external data
内部データと外部データを組み合わせることができます
so what
だから何
finally
ついに
What about the results of our analysis?
分析の結果はどうでしょうか?
That's it
それでおしまい
that is
あれは
If we only use the health insurance database
健康保険データベースのみを利用する場合
This is a
これは
This analysis is a comparative
この分析は比較です
Simplified Analysis
簡易分析
because he failed to take into account two important variables
彼は 2 つの重要な変数を考慮に入れていなかったため、
smoking and drinking
喫煙と飲酒
So under such analysis
したがって、そのような分析の下では
we got this code foam pillow
このフォーム枕を手に入れました
Relationship with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease
慢性閉塞性肺疾患との関係
is 1.7
1.7です
What does that mean
どういう意味ですか
That is to say, people who have foam pillows
つまり、低反発枕を使っている人は、
he will get this later
彼は後でこれを手に入れるでしょう
Patients with COPD
COPD患者
I've mispoken
言い間違えた
The risk that he will get a proxy pillow at a later date
後で代理枕を手に入れるリスク
is without COPD
COPDはない
patients without chronic obstructive pulmonary disease
慢性閉塞性肺疾患のない患者
1.7 times
1.7倍
That is, if you have chronic obstructive pulmonary disease
つまり、慢性閉塞性肺疾患がある場合
you will have higher
あなたはもっと高くなります
risk to get this bandage
この包帯を手に入れるのは危険です
This multiple is 1.7 times
この倍率は1.7倍です
But what about such an analysis?
しかし、そのような分析はどうでしょうか？
is a rough analysis
大まかな分析です
Simplified Analysis
簡易分析
because it's only based on the health insurance database
健康保険データベースのみに基づいているため、
There is no information about smoking and drinking
喫煙や飲酒に関する情報はありません
So if you use the National Health Interview Survey
したがって、国民健康面接調査を使用すると、
it has all the data
すべてのデータが入っています
But its data volume is relatively small
ただしデータ量は比較的少ない
Its Sumpo Size
スンポサイズ
Its sample size is relatively small
サンプルサイズは比較的小さいです
The result you get is something like this
得られる結果は次のようなものです
what does it mean
どういう意味ですか
that is, chronic obstructive
つまり慢性閉塞性です
What about non-disease patients?
病気ではない患者の場合はどうでしょうか？
His risk of getting banding
縞模様の銃疾患にかかるリスク
is not chronic obstructive
慢性閉塞性ではない
2.83 times that of non-disease patients
非疾患患者の2.83倍
This risk increases
このリスクは増大します
But it should be noted that
しかし、注意しなければならないのは、
its central limit theorem
その中心極限定理
The one in the normal distribution
正規分布のもの
What about the smoking variant?
喫煙のバリエーションはどうですか？
that width
その幅
Just imagine the normal width
通常の幅を想像してください
also quite big
それもかなり大きい
This means that your result
これは、結果が
because your sample size
なぜならサンプルサイズが
Everyone remembers that it consumes 1/M more, right?
消費量が 1/M 増えるのは皆さん覚えていますよね？
So your sample size is relatively small
したがって、サンプルサイズは比較的小さいです
so your error
だからあなたの間違い
Your sampling error will be relatively large
サンプリング誤差は比較的大きくなります
So 1.56
つまり1.56
So even though you have such a big risk
ですから、それほど大きなリスクを抱えているにもかかわらず、
But because your uncertainty is also great
でも君の不確実性も大きいから
So we have to calculate a ratio in the end
したがって、最終的に比率を計算する必要があります
This ratio is generally greater than 2
この比率は通常 2 より大きくなります
We'd better do this significantly
これは大幅にやったほうがいいです
That is to say, the p value is small
つまりp値が小さい
The p value just mentioned
先ほど述べたp値
be less than 0.05
0.05未満であること
So what is the current ratio?
では、流動比率はいくらでしょうか？
That is to say its statistic itself
つまりその統計そのもの
the estimator itself compared to its uncertainty
推定量自体とその不確実性の比較
Compared with its stand arrow
スタンドアローとの比較
This ratio does not exceed 2
この比率は 2 を超えません
So its result is not significant enough
したがって、その結果は十分に重要ではありません
so i can't draw any firm conclusions
だから明確な結論は出せない
But if you use the two
しかし、この2つを使用すると、
This combination of internal and external data
この内部データと外部データの組み合わせ
Combining health insurance database with
健康保険データベースとの連携
The data from the National Health Interview Survey
国民健康面接調査のデータ
The result you get is this
あなたが得る結果はこれです
this
これ
chronic obstructive pulmonary disease causes
慢性閉塞性肺疾患の原因
Risks of Ribbon Pillows
リボン枕のリスク
This multiple is almost 1.9 times
この倍率はほぼ1.9倍です
but its this
でもそれはこれ
sampling error
サンプリングエラー
Everyone remembers the one with the normal distribution
正規分布のものは誰もが覚えています
that width that error
その幅、そのエラー
also dropped to only 0.11
わずか0.11まで低下した
Only a tenth of the original size is smaller
元のサイズの 10 分の 1 だけ小さくなります
so what
だから何
This will make your
これにより、
pen value
ペンの値
your
あなたの
Estimated value divided by its standarrow pen value
推定値をスタンドアロー ペンの値で割った値
yes
はい
more than 10
10以上
so it's very, very significant
それはとてもとても重要なことです
So its p-value is 0.05
したがって、その p 値は 0.05 です。
So this illustrates this
これはこれを示しています
you combine
あなたは組み合わせる
External materials
外部資料
analysis is helpful
分析は役に立ちます
can reduce your sampling error
サンプリングエラーを減らすことができます
I think I'll just use these two examples
これら 2 つの例だけを使用すると思います
with everyone
みんなとともに
explain
説明
what i do
私がやること
that's statistics
それは統計です
doing something
なんかやってる
Of course, this is just my personal one-sided
もちろんこれは私の個人的な一方的な意見です
very one-sided things
非常に一方的なもの
Let's see if you have any questions
何か質問があれば聞いてみましょう
ok thank you
わかりました、ありがとう
Some of Mr. Chen's
チェン氏の作品の一部
made a with us
私たちと一緒に作りました
equal to an overview
概要に等しい
for this statistical
この統計については
some things you can do
あなたにできること
that's how we are now
それが今の私たちです
Our organizers are ready
私たちの主催者は準備ができています
scientific magazine
科学雑誌
There are
がある
There are about 10 copies, so every guest who asks a question
10部ほどありますので、ご質問いただくゲスト全員に
can get 1 copy
1部入手可能
So we can start from this sequence of questions
この一連の質問から始めましょう
We will be giving away this hope to finish the 10 copies
10部完成するこの希望を捧げます
Okay, is there anyone in the audience right now?
はい、今聴衆に誰かいますか？
this way first thank you
まずはこちらへ、ありがとう
Hello, Mr. Chong, let me ask you about the application examples behind you
こんにちは、チョンさん、あなたの応用例についてお聞きしたいのですが
In the approach of ground acceleration for earthquake engineering
地震工学における地盤加速度のアプローチ
Is your R the epicenter or the epicenter? I’m just curious.
あなたのRは震源地ですか?それとも震源地ですか?ちょっと興味があります。
this is the first little problem
これが最初の小さな問題です
The second part is whether there is a way to do anti-authentication
2 番目の部分は、反認証を行う方法があるかどうかです。
For example, Taipei City is in the side-to-side valuation
たとえば、台北市は横並びの評価を受けています。
Is it relatively larger
比較的大きいかな
Because everyone in Taipei knows that there is a formation amplification effect
台北の誰もがフォーメーション増幅効果があることを知っているからです
Is it possible to improve the reliability and validity?
信頼性や妥当性を高めることは可能でしょうか？
and then go further to give feedback
さらにフィードバックを提供します
your original model
あなたのオリジナルモデル
Thanks
ありがとう
Yes, I think this R should refer to
はい、この R を参照する必要があると思います
Did you just ask about politics?
政治について聞いただけですか？
It's still Zhengyuan, right?
まだ正遠ですよね？
because you just said politics
さっき政治のこと言ったから
So I'm curious to say
だから私は言いたいのです
Why not Zhengyuan
なぜ鄭遠ではないのか
Zhengyuan is the real legend drama
正遠は本物の伝説のドラマです
this is normal
これは正常です
Yes, it is actually divided into two dramas
はい、実際には2つのドラマがあります
Actually, I'm not very clear about the details.
実は、詳しいことはよくわかっていません。
one should be what you mean
1つはあなたの言いたいこと通りになるはずです
Just the picture I just had
さっき持ってた写真だけ
that is to say it has
つまりそれはある
when they define the play
彼らが遊びを定義するとき
There are indeed some differences
確かにいくつかの違いがあります
defined method
定義されたメソッド
that one is political
あれは政治的なものだ
One possibility is the political source you mentioned
可能性の 1 つは、あなたが言及した政治的情報源です
So both are used
なので両方使われます
right
右
The second point is that
2つ目のポイントは、
what you just said is
あなたが今言ったことは
If according to the characteristics of this address
このアドレスの特性によると
For example, what is pious or something?
たとえば、敬虔とは何ですか？
Can I get it from here again?
またここから入手できますか？
I think that's what we're here for
それが私たちがここにいる目的だと思います
That is to say, to take the characteristics of this place
つまり、この場所の特徴を活かすために
want
欲しい
access to our forecast
予測へのアクセス
You can get some more precise analysis
より正確な分析が可能になります
right
右
Then you say in this from
それからあなたはこの中でこう言います
What about getting some corrections
修正してもらったらどうでしょうか
i think it is
それはそうですね
In order to get more accurate predictions
より正確な予測を得るために
right
右
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
Everyone, the next one
みなさん、次は
Teacher Chen
チェン先生
i have two questions
質問が2つあります
The first question is to say
最初の質問はこう言います
when you're predicting low
低い予想をしているとき
you have already happened
あなたはすでに起こっています
So you collect a lot of data
それでたくさんのデータを集めます
for analysis
分析用
So can you predict
それで予測できますか
Who did he say would happen
起こるだろうと彼は誰が言った？
There is a second question
2 番目の質問があります
in case he happens
彼が起こった場合に備えて
you know where he is
彼がどこにいるか知っていますか
but can you predict
でも予測できますか
How far can he go
彼はどこまで行けるだろうか
range of influence
影響範囲
Yes, then I have to type these two questions
はい、それではこれら 2 つの質問を入力する必要があります
i didn't do it
私はしませんでした
Yes because there may be some
はい、いくつかあるかもしれないので
doing such a problem
そんな問題をやってる
For example, predict
たとえば、予測します
when hypoxia occurs
低酸素が発生すると
Then
それから
Also, his positive wave
また、彼のポジティブな波動は、
maybe
多分
How far does it radiate
どこまで放射するのか
But I must say I have no experience with either of these
しかし、私はこれらのいずれについても経験がないと言わざるを得ません
because
なぜなら
that is
あれは
The earthquakes I have come into contact with are all biased
私が接した地震はどれも偏りがある
so-called earthquake engineering
いわゆる地震工学
as you just said
あなたが今言ったように
an earthquake that has occurred
発生した地震
then we go from it
それからそこから出発します
and look at its acceleration against the ground
地面に対する加速度を見てください
and its impact on buildings
そして建物への影響
what we studied
私たちが勉強したこと
I didn't come across some
いくつかは見つからなかった
Possibly study some of the earthquake itself
おそらく地震自体の一部を研究する
some scientific nature
何らかの科学的性質
when will it happen
いつ起こりますか
And then how does its shock wave propagate
そして、その衝撃波はどのように伝播するのでしょうか
I don't have that
私はそれを持っていません
no contact
接触無し
right
右
Thanks
ありがとう
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
the third one is here
3つ目はここにあります
Wait a moment
等一下
Hello Mr. Chen
こんにちは、チェンさん
Here
ここ
Where
どこ
good
良い
sorry
ごめん
sorry sorry
ごめんごめん
like this
このような
because i saw you doing this earthquake
あなたがこの地震をしているのを見たから
this model
このモデル
That's because I just happened to be a while ago
たまたまさっきまでいたから
We just had the sudden thought of saying
私たちは突然こう言うことを思いつきました
Let's just use that
それをそのまま使いましょう
Low power consumption unlimited power and that
低消費電力で無制限に電力を供給できること
the chipped one
欠けたもの
Accelerometer
加速度計
It's a six-axis accelerometer
6軸加速度センサーです
to put in some fixed position
一定の位置に置く
Then it becomes a lot of distribution points
そうするとたくさんの配布ポイントになります
This will form a sensor network
これによりセンサーネットワークが形成されます
and then to sense those points above
そして上記のポイントを感知するために
The vibrating Megane2
振動する Megane2
The strength of its government, etc.
政府の強さなど
But so I see say this
でも、なるほど、こう言うのですね
Mr. Chen, you are here
チェンさん、来ましたよ
I have done a lot of information on this
これについてはたくさんの情報を提供しました
It should be ten years, right?
もう10年になるはずですよね？
your sensor
あなたのセンサー
Because the main thing is your sensor
重要なのはセンサーだから
You still have the value it returns later
後で返される値がまだ残っています
your values
あなたの価値観
Mainly how can you be sure to say
主にどのようにして確実に言うことができますか
its values ​​are believable
その価値観は信頼できる
Because if you say that you use the accelerometer to judge
加速度センサーを使って判断すると言ったら
In fact, there will be a big problem, that is,
実は、大きな問題が起きるのです。
Not necessarily an earthquake
必ずしも地震が起こるとは限らない
Maybe it's just a landslide today
もしかしたら今日は土砂崩れかもしれない
Or maybe there is a project nearby
あるいは近くにプロジェクトがあるかもしれません
Big trucks drive by and he still vibrates
大きなトラックが通り過ぎても、彼の振動はまだ続いている
Under such circumstances, Mr. Chen, your materials
このような状況の中で、陳さん、資料をお願いします。
Have you done this kind of filtering such as reliability and so on?
信頼性などのフィルタリングは行っていますか？
In fact, they originally said that the data
実際、彼らは当初、データは次のように述べていました。
They received confirmation in this database
このデータベースで確認を受け取りました
he is an earthquake
彼は地震だ
Because every time an earthquake occurs, the Central Meteorological Bureau will announce
地震が起きるたびに中央氣象局が発表するからです。
So sure it's an earthquake
それは確かに地震です
Right, so they're all sure
そう、だから彼らはみんな確信しているんだ
These surface accelerations from this earthquake
この地震によるこれらの表面加速度
they will be included in this database
それらはこのデータベースに含まれます
So if what you just said is some other landslide
では、あなたが今言った地滑りが別のものであるならば、
Or a big truck has been driven
あるいは大型トラックが運転されていた
Or the MRT has been opened, the high-speed rail has been opened
あるいはMRTが開通した、高速鉄道が開通した
Then they should not be included in this earthquake
それなら今回の地震には含めるべきではない
included, so they have to do some manual judgment
が含まれているため、手動で判断する必要があります
to themselves and then snap out some unnecessary parts
自分自身に合わせて、不要な部分をスナップして取り除きます
Yes, when they were building this database
はい、このデータベースを構築していたとき
should do this
これをすべきです
OK OK OK
OK OK OK
Right, well, what about your accelerometer itself?
そうですね、加速度計自体はどうですか?
Are there any problems that need to be corrected?
修正する必要がある問題はありますか?
Because of this when we actually do
このため、実際にやってみると、
This problem happened, it seems to have heard them talking
この問題が起こりました、彼らが話しているのが聞こえたようです
But this is not our specialty.
しかし、これは私たちの専門分野ではありません。
then they seem to have listened
それから彼らは聞いてくれたようです
as if i heard them say
まるで彼らが言うのを聞いたかのように
they need to do some corrections or something
彼らはいくつかの修正か何かをする必要がある
Yes, assuming the information they provide should be
はい、提供される情報が次であると仮定します。
it's right it's right
そうです、そうです
A certain design is correct from which statistical analysis
統計分析から特定の設計は正しい
Yeah
うん
The one behind just now, and the one who waits a little longer
さっき後ろにいる人、もう少し待っている人
just a little bit of advice
ちょっとしたアドバイス
That is to say, in statistics
つまり統計的には
part that is said to be man-made
人工的に作られたとされる部分に属する
It's like talking about earthquakes when I was studying in high school
高校時代に地震について話していたようなものだ
It's some water currents hitting plates.
プレートに当たる水流です。
But if say, hypothesis says need experiment say
しかし、もし仮説が言うなら、実験が必要だと言う
is it security
セキュリティですか
How shockproof is it?
耐衝撃性はどのくらいですか?
that might be
それはそうかもしれない
Bo Jun's bomb is under the ground
ボジュンの爆弾は地下にある
Explosion at the bottom of the sea
海底での爆発
The kind of vibration that spread out in Taiwan
台湾に広がった振動のようなもの
it's also possible
それも可能です
that or
それか
for some military precautions
いくつかの軍事的予防措置のため
or experiment
または実験
such data
そのようなデータ
how to include
含める方法
That and the gentleman just said
それと紳士は今こう言いました
If it is possible to do so
それが可能であれば
If the operation experiment
動作実験なら
Is it possible to predict
予測することは可能ですか
Naturally occurring and man-made situations
自然発生的な状況と人為的な状況
because why is it so small
なんでこんなに小さいんだろう
Because I often spend three thousand midnight
夜中に三千時を過ごすことが多いから
half done washing
洗濯が半分終わった
Why another earthquake
なぜまた地震が起こるのか
that's too often
那太頻繁
I feel that it is the same as the theory of studying in high school before
以前の高校の勉強のセオリーと同じような気がします
a little weird
少し変な
so i want to say
だから私は言いたいです
Is it an artificial perception
それは人工的な認識ですか
i want them this
これが欲しいです
as long as i just said
私が今言った限りでは
That is to say, they should just consider
つまり、彼らは次のように考えればよいのです。
caused by the earthquake
地震によって引き起こされた
surface acceleration
地表加速度
they don't think about it
彼らはそれについて考えていません
what you just said
あなたが今言ったこと
human factors
人的要因
let's add
追加しましょう
The man for the nuclear bomb test
核爆弾実験をした男
Will he form energy dollars
彼はエネルギードルを形成するだろうか
Then the shares I form are
すると、私が形成する株式は次のようになります。
I don't know
わからない
Because I do not know
分からないから
I don't know if Taiwan is still conducting nuclear tests
台湾が今も核実験を行っているかどうかは分からない
this
これ
I think this chance should be less
この機会は少なくてもいいと思う
Of course, if it's from North Korea or somewhere else
もちろん、それが北朝鮮か他の場所からのものであれば、
then i don't know
それなら分からない
Does the region have this
この地域にはこんなのがあるのか
Yes but this
はい、でもこれ
i think both
両方とも思います
none of them will appear again
それらはいずれも再び表示されません
The one we are analyzing now
私たちが今分析しているもの
In the so-called surface acceleration data of earthquakes
いわゆる地震の表面加速度データ
In other words, statistics and computers
つまり、統計とコンピュータ
Our statistics mean
私たちの統計が意味するのは、
we see our purpose
私たちは自分たちの目的を理解しています
Our purpose is only to analyze earthquakes
私たちの目的は地震を解析することだけです
right
右
Hello
こんにちは
right here
ここにあります
Just learned that thread
そのスレッドを知ったばかりです
When you say that thread treasure is very much needed
糸宝がとても必要だと言うと
Which means he had the opportunity to study the life of this individual
つまり、彼はこの人物の人生を研究する機会があったということです
But health insurance can solve personal life
しかし、健康保険は私生活を解決できる
on top of the male
男性の上に
other human life
他の人間の人生
After continuing to study
勉強を続けた上で
When an old man comes and goes, he still holds
老人が来るとき、彼はまだ抱きしめています
The person who holds this condition
この条件を抱えている人は
will
意思
In other words, the impact on the whole
つまり全体への影響
Then we are now in Taiwan
そして今は台湾にいます
The former health team leader Yang Zhiqiang also said
元保健チームリーダーの楊志強氏もこう語った。
Planetary aging in Taiwan
台湾の惑星老化
2.82 million
282万
in this situation
この状況では
Our Mr. Fu Daren
私たちのフー・ダーレン氏
poor kiln lady
貧しい窯の女性
If they are like this
彼らがこんな感じだったら
This angle is accumulating
この角度は蓄積されています
Cumulative to zero rigid angle
累積剛角ゼロ
at best
せいぜい
what do we do
私たちは何をしますか
to solve the problem
この問題を解決するために
For example, the Anning Project
たとえば、アニングプロジェクト
Is it going to pass
通りますか？
Is this the case in Taiwan?
台湾でもそうなんですか？
That is to say, I want to ask you to say
つまり、こう言ってもらいたいのです。
between you personally and collectively
あなた個人と集団の間で
place to take
要採取的地方
I think this is probably what people in their health policy have to consider
おそらくこれは、医療政策を担当する人々が考慮しなければならないことだと思います
Then the only thing statistics can do is to provide them with some real-world data.
その場合、統計ができることは、現実世界のデータを提供することだけです。
right
右
Then as you just said, prolonging personal life or
それから、今おっしゃったように、私生活を延ばすとか、
For the whole country and society because of the senile dementia you just mentioned
国全体、社会全体にとって、今おっしゃった老人性認知症のために。
How to balance the diseases of aging
加齢に伴う病気のバランスをどう整えるか
I think their health policy will make policy based on our data
彼らの健康政策は私たちのデータに基づいて政策を決定すると思います
right
右
good
良い
learn
学び
There are often problems with missing children
子どもの行方不明問題が頻繁に起きている
For example, we are distinguishing between healthy people and
たとえば、健康な人と健康な人を区別しています。
sick person that
病気の人、それは
When doing grouping, there are some missing children, so there are some statistics
グループ化を行うと、行方不明の子も発生するため、統計がいくつかあります。
If the method encounters a shortage, he can only use this
メソッドが不足している場合、彼はこれしか使用できません
Sampo sacrificed him
サンポは彼を犠牲にした
But we are not willing to sacrifice too much SAMPO
しかし、私たちはSAMPOをあまり犠牲にするつもりはありません
Because sometimes it is not easy to obtain, so is there a time like this?
なかなか手に入らないこともあるので、こういう時もあるのかな？
Some ways to overcome these problems
これらの問題を克服するいくつかの方法
Yes, very, very much, yes, like what I just said
はい、とても、とても、はい、今言ったことと同じです
EM algorithm is very suitable
EMアルゴリズムは非常に適しています
because what I just said
なぜなら、私が今言ったことは、
The EM algorithm says
EMアルゴリズムは言う
Some parts of your model can be without
モデルの一部の部分は省略できます
I see, the deficiency you just mentioned means there is no
なるほど、今おっしゃった不足というのは、
You see it, right?
わかりますよね？
So you're in the EM algorithm
つまり、あなたは EM アルゴリズムの中にいます
What about the first step? You can put the
最初のステップはどうでしょうか?
The part seen finds a way to use a reasonable
見られる部分は、合理的な使用方法を見つけます
This missing piece will replace it, right?
この欠けている部分が代わりになりますよね？
Then go get a reasonable
それから合理的なものを手に入れてください
Yes, there are many other ways
はい、他にもたくさんの方法があります
that is to say in this
つまりこの中では
The lack of fat you just mentioned, the loss of fat?
先ほどおっしゃった脂肪の不足、脂肪の減少ですか？
This is the focus of statistics and a study of statistics
これが統計の焦点であり、統計の研究です
right
右
So I think you should be able to find this kind of method easily
したがって、この種の方法は簡単に見つかるはずだと思います
Okay, we have two questions here.
さて、ここで質問が 2 つあります。
First off, I'm sorry
まず初めに、ごめんなさい
Literary advice means when you
文学的なアドバイスとは、次のような場合を意味します。
A little more information about medicine
薬についてもう少し詳しく
When you have more information and more information about smoking and drinking
喫煙と飲酒についてさらに詳しい情報が得られたら
in the whole model
モデル全体で
When you have some other relevant and useful information
他に関連性のある有益な情報がある場合
With this strip pillow and this lung condition
このストリップ枕とこの肺の状態では
Then you probably shouldn't increase
だったら増やさないほうがいいかもしれない
Because of the added information
情報が追加されたので
So you probably shouldn't increase
したがって、おそらく追加しないでください
That is to say, foam pillows affect lung diseases.
つまり、低反発枕は肺疾患に影響を与えるのです。
this variation
このバリエーション
In fact you are lowered Virgin much lower
実際、あなたはヴァージンのレベルをはるかに下回っています
but here's the problem
しかし、ここに問題があります
I kind of disagree with your Standard Arrow
私はあなたの標準的な矢にはちょっと同意しません
able to lower that much
そこまで下げることができる
It is because when you have a lot of information
情報がたくさんあるからこそ、
does not represent a change in your main parameter
メインパラメータの変更を表すものではありません
should be bigger
もっと大きいはずです
so i have a little doubt
それで少し疑問があります
Against my decades of statistical experience
私の数十年にわたる統計経験に反して
so i don't quite agree
だから私はあまり同意しません
That change can be so dramatic
その変化はとても劇的なものになる可能性があります
This is the first point
これが最初のポイントです
Second, if you have earthquake data
次に、地震データがある場合
when your different site
別のサイトの場合
in different intensities
さまざまな強度で
I suggest you take another factor into consideration
別の要素を検討することをお勧めします
That is to say, you travel from Zheng Yuan to Taipei City
つまり、鄭元から台北市まで移動します。
When you go to different places in Kaohsiung
高雄のいろんなところに行くときは
It this Pass
それはこのパスです
It has different Pass
パスが違います
Where the Pass passes
パスが通過する場所
that average change
その平均的な変化
That change can probably be described a little bit
その変化はおそらく少し説明できるでしょう
Describe the change of that Pass
そのパスの変更について説明してください
very important
とても重要な
OK
OK
right
右
so i suggest you first
だから最初にあなたに提案します
Thank you very very much Mr. Chen
チェンさん、本当にありがとうございました
And Mr. Chen is a very experienced
そしてチェン先生は非常に経験豊富です
The lifted statistician
持ち上げられた統計学者
I was taken aback by the question he just asked
私は彼のたった今の質問にびっくりしました
right
右
first question
最初の質問
that is to say, i admit that is to say
つまり、はい、それは認めます
We do this for different databases
さまざまなデータベースに対してこれを行います
combine
結合
Companation actually requires some assumptions
実際、会社にはいくつかの前提条件が必要です
how is your result
結果はどうですか
to some extent
ある程度
will be influenced by your assumptions
あなたの仮定に影響されるだろう
Then of course we are here
それならもちろん私たちはここにいます
because our assumptions about our assumptions
なぜなら、私たちの仮定についての私たちの仮定が
These two databases
この 2 つのデータベース
The material it contains is quite homogenous
含まれる材料は非常に均質です
So that is to say, such a combibe
つまりそういうコンビ
like a lot
たくさんのように
Especially as big as the health insurance database
特に健康保険データベースと同じくらい大きい
as soon as you bring it in
持ち込むとすぐに
can force a lot
多くのことを強制できる
But I fully admit that
しかし、私はそれを完全に認めます
totally agree that is to say
つまり、完全に同意します
This is of course an assumption that
もちろんこれは仮定です
Assuming the two databases
2 つのデータベースがあると仮定すると、
National Health Insurance Database and National Health Interview
国民健康保険データベースと国民健康面接
very homogenous
非常 homogenous
Like Teacher Chen just said
チェン先生が今言ったように
Actually, I think what you mean is to say
実際、あなたが言いたいのは次のようなことだと思います
In fact, if the two are different
実際、この二つが違うとしたら、
It's a bit different population, right?
ちょっと人口が違うんですよね？
So their own parameter values
したがって、独自のパラメータ値
maybe it's different
違うかもしれない
he himself will have a variation
彼自身にもバリエーションがあるだろう
so you bring it in
だからあなたはそれを持ち込む
May instead increase variation
むしろバリエーションが増えるかもしれない
not reduce information
情報を減らさない
then i totally agree
それなら私も完全に同意します
it is possible
可能です
But this means that it needs to be considered
しかし、これは考慮する必要があることを意味します
another model
別のモデル
For example, mature model or something
例えば熟女モデルとか
Then consider the question
それから質問を考えてみましょう
That is, if we want to combine
つまり、組み合わせたい場合は、
are two very different populations
2 つの非常に異なる集団です
how would that be
それはどうだろうか
ok then your second question
はい、それでは 2 番目の質問です
Actually I just skipped it
実はただ飛ばしていただけだった
I didn't talk about it, I just said it. In fact, we were here later.
それについて話したのではなく、ただ言っただけです実際、私たちは後でここに来ました
This regression model of this
この回帰モデルは
It's Fariousion's this
ファリオシオンですよこれ
As for the dismantling, we actually considered it later.
解体については、実は後から検討しました。
You just talked about the problem of this Pass
あなたはちょうどこのパスの問題について話しました
We have also considered the issue of Pass
パスの問題も検討しました
It is different Effects for different side stations
サイドステーションごとに効果が異なります
The impact of its Pass
パスの影響
So this will make this
それでこれはこれになります
will make this
これを作ります
The prediction error will be further reduced
予測誤差はさらに減少します
teacher long time no see
先生お久しぶりです
Yes, long time no see. It's my master student.
はい、お久しぶりです、私の修士課程の生徒です。
right
右
I just heard the teacher mention the total probability theorem
先生が全確率定理について言及しているのを聞いたところです
theorem it can be integrated
積分できる定理
right
右
Integrate data from different databases
さまざまなデータベースからのデータを統合する
For example, when some databases are very large
たとえば、一部のデータベースが非常に大きい場合、
Information about my different consultations every day
日々のさまざまな相談内容をご案内します
and then restore it
そしてそれを復元します
Then combine them to get a more accurate number
次に、それらを組み合わせてより正確な数値を取得します
Just upgrade that database
そのデータベースをアップグレードするだけです
The computational efficiency looks like this
計算効率はこんな感じ
Your question is about using the full chance
あなたの質問はチャンスを最大限に活用することについてです
Can improve the efficiency of operation
業務効率を向上できる
Yes, we didn't actually consider
はい、実際には考慮していませんでした
Operational efficiency
業務効率化
Our side is actually
私たちの側は実は
think of a way
方法を考えます
Link internal data with external data
内部データと外部データをリンクする
So just use the law of large numbers
だから大数の法則を使ってください
Then use the formula of total probability
次に、合計確率の公式を使用します
that's all
それで全部です
so
それで
Actually I feel like
実際のところ、私は次のように感じています
as if he could
あたかも彼ができるかのように
past database
過去のデータベース
When improving operational efficiency
業務効率を向上させる場合
It's all about hardware or
それはすべてハードウェアに関するものであるか、
write programs to improve
改善するためのプログラムを書く
But today I heard full of special thoughts saying
でも今日は特別な思いが詰まった言葉を聞きました
He can use some statistical theorems
彼はいくつかの統計定理を使用できる
Then to improve his computing efficiency
次に、コンピューティング効率を向上させるために
Thank you, teacher
ありがとう、先生
Okay, let's talk in private, yeah
オーケー、プライベートで話しましょう、ええ
And here are two more. The last two.
あと 2 つ、最後の 2 つです。
Hello teacher, may I ask
こんにちは、先生、聞いてもいいですか
Although the EM algorithm can improve the maximization of our target cold accommodation
EM アルゴリズムは目標の寒さ調節能力の最大化を向上させることができますが、
with optimization, but it sometimes has its drawbacks
最適化を使用しますが、場合によっては欠点もあります
The calculation is complex and the convergence rate is relatively slow, and it will depend on the cold weather of the initial parameters
計算は複雑で、収束速度は比較的遅く、初期パラメータの寒冷気候に依存します。
For reference, the part in E-STEP will not affect us
参考までに、E-STEPの部分は影響しません。
The strength of the interval so far, thank you
これまでのインターバルの力、ありがとう
What you just said is absolutely correct, that is, the E-EM algorithm has a
あなたが今言ったことは完全に正しいです。つまり、E-EM アルゴリズムには
There are some disadvantages, for example, the biggest disadvantage is its
デメリットもいくつかありますが、例えば最大のデメリットは
The operation speed is slower because
動作速度が遅くなるため、
Right, because it's an algorithm we call linear
そうです、これは線形と呼ばれるアルゴリズムだからです
it is slower
それは遅いです
But what you just said is that
しかし、あなたが今言ったことは、
E-EM algorithm
E-EM演算法
your final question is
あなたの最後の質問は
That is to say, we have to rely on his initial parameters
つまり、彼の初期パラメータに依存する必要があります。
make assumptions
仮定を立てる
Will this affect our ability to get
これは私たちの入手能力に影響しますか?
The strength of the newcomer interval
新人の間の強さ
yes yes yes you mentioned the new range
はい、はい、新しい範囲について言及しました
What about the new range?
新しいレンジはどうですか？
I don't think it matters, that is to say
それは重要ではないと思います、つまり
If once you're sure he's
一度彼がそうだと確信したら
Convergent at last
ついに収束
Then finally you can use
その後、最終的に使用できるようになります
We have this formula
この公式があります
We have this certain formula
この特定の公式があります
It can be used to calculate his newcomer range
彼の新人の範囲を計算するために使用できます
so there is no problem
だから問題ないよ
right
右
should be
あるべきです
I know this video will be there
このビデオが掲載されることは知っています
PTT if the teacher is willing
先生がよろしければ PTT
The Folklore Department should be able to
民俗部門は次のことができるはずです。
can handle
扱える
nod over there
そこでうなずく
good
良い
no problem
問題ない
Well, if we have
そうですね、もし持っていれば
Send out all the magazines
雑誌をすべて発送する
before ending today's speech
今日のスピーチを終える前に
I want to make a preview before the event
イベント前に下見をしたい
Our next month is May
来月は5月です
The Feast of Knowledge is on May 29th
知識の饗宴は5月29日です
by our Institute of Biochemistry
私たちの生化学研究所による
This topic is completely different
この話題は全く違います
Is Wu Shixiong Distinguished Researcher
呉世雄は特別研究員です
So here in the life sciences group
ここライフサイエンスグループでは
The topic of his lecture is
彼の講義のテーマは
The relationship between sugar molecules and life
糖分子と生命の関係
So this is from our life science group
これは私たちのライフサイエンスグループからです
a speech
スピーチ
Here we would like to thank our keynote speaker today
ここで、本日の基調講演者に感謝したいと思います。
Teacher Chen
チェン先生
Teacher Chen Yihao
チェン・イーハオ先生
Thanks
ありがとう
give us a
私たちに与えてください
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
yes
はい
very special speech
とても特別なスピーチ
Then thank you all the guests
それではゲストの皆様、ありがとうございました
again
また
We hope to see you all again next month
来月また皆さんにお会いできることを楽しみにしています
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう